<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Supernatural Gifts</name>
        <update version="0.0.5">
            <file name="supernatural-gifts.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/supernatural-gifts/supernatural-gifts.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Blessing of Lunar Father" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MAGIC_ITEM_BLESSING_OF_LUNAR_FATHER">
        <description>
            <p>After consuming the heart of the defeated Lunar Lycanthropy Werewolf Alpha, "The All Devourer" undergoes a transformative experience, gaining a potent mutational power-up with both benefits and drawbacks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Enhanced Vigor:</b></i> Your Constitution score increases by +2, maximum of 22, and you gain advantage on Constitution saving throws.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Necrotic Resilience:</b></i> You gain resistance to necrotic damage, and you can use your reaction to absorb necrotic energy, healing for half the damage you would have taken.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Uncontrollable Transformation:</b></i> During periods of a full moon or when exposed to intense moonlight, you must make a DC 16 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, you unwillingly transform into a werewolf for 1 hour, losing control of your actions. Your alignment temporarily shifts to chaotic evil nonetheless during these transformations.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Lunar Dependency:</b></i> You become reliant on moonlight to maintain your strength. In the absence of moonlight, you suffer a -2 penalty to all of your ability scores and deal 1d8 necrotic damage to yourself at the start of each of your turns. You can't benefit long or short rest in this situation. This effect is negated as soon as you are exposed to moonlight again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Blessing</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="2" />
            <stat name="constitution:max" value="22" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Wolf Father's Glacial Inner Dormancy" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MAGIC_ITEM_WOLF_FATHERS_GLACIAL_INNER_DORMANCY">
        <description>
            <p>This technique is bestowed upon the practitioners by the ancient spirits of the Wolf Father. By invoking this technique, the practitioner enters a state of deep inner dormancy akin to the tranquility of glacial stillness.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Tranquility:</b></i> In this state, the mind becomes impervious to the chaotic influences of rage and fury, allowing for unparalleled focus and concentration amidst the storm of battle. You gain +2 to Insight checks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Essence Circuit Disruption:</b></i> You force your opponents weak will to shut its state. Upon usage, you can force a creature that is within a reach of you to roll a Wisdom Saving Throw. If they fail this throw, the creature becomes loosened and lost its concentration with ongoing state. For your next attack rolls against this creature becomes advantaged. You can use this feature number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Blessing</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="insight:misc" value="2" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HAILJOE_RACIAL_TRAIT_ESSENCE_CIRCUIT_DISRUPTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Essence Circuit Disruption" type="Racial Trait" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_RACIAL_TRAIT_ESSENCE_CIRCUIT_DISRUPTION">
        <compendium display="false" />
        <description>
            <p>You force your opponents weak will to shut its state. Upon usage, you can force a creature that is within a reach of you to roll a Wisdom Saving Throw. If they fail this throw, the creature becomes loosened and lost its concentration with ongoing state. For your next attack rolls against this creature becomes advantaged. You can use this feature number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You can use a bonus action to end the state of your opponent and lose its concentration. If nothing is holding you aloft at the end of your turn, you fall. Chosen creature that is within a reach of you rolls a Wisdom Saving Throw. On failed save, creature becomes loosened and lost its concentration with ongoing state. Also, your next attack rolls against this creature becomes advantaged.</description>
    	</sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Blessings of the Frost Maiden: Oathsworn " type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MAGIC_ITEM_BOTFM_OATHSWORN">
        <description>
            <p>The Frost Maiden has bestowed upon Vulcan the ability to harness the power of ice in addition to his mastery over fire. This blessing grants him new abilities and enhances his existing powers, allowing him to wield both elements with harmony.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Frost Resilience:</b></i> You have resistane to cold damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Frostfire Surge:</b></i> As an action, you can unleash a burst of frostfire in a 20-foot radius centered on himself. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + proficiency bonus + Charisma modifier). On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 fire damage and 4d8 cold damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and is not pushed.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Blessing</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HAILJOE_RACIAL_TRAIT_FROSTFIRE_SURGE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Frostfire Surge" type="Racial Trait" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_RACIAL_TRAIT_FROSTFIRE_SURGE">
        <compendium display="false" />
        <description>
            <p>With a swift, forceful gesture, the caster releases a swirling torrent of icy flames that erupts in a spectacular display. The surge races forward, creating a path of frozen fire that burns with an intense cold. Anything caught in its wake is simultaneously scorched by the searing heat and frozen by the biting cold, making it particularly devastating to both flesh and metal. As an action, you can unleash a burst of frostfire in a 20-foot cone. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + proficiency bonus + Charisma modifier). On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 fire damage and 4d8 cold damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and is not pushed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can use an action to unleash a burst of frostfire. Each creature in 20-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw equals DC {{frostfire surge:dc}}. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 fire damage and 4d8 cold damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and is not pushed.</description>
    	</sheet>
        <rules>
			<stat name="frostfire surge:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="frostfire surge:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="frostfire surge:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
    </element>

	<element name="Hive Mind Perfection Abruption" type="Racial Trait" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_RACIAL_TRAIT_HIVE_MIND_PERFECTION_ABRUPTION">
        <description>
            <p>The result of a chaotic event within the hive mind caused your individual will to splinter and flee, aborting the process of perfection. Though the Ceremorphosis was not completed, certain manifestations of this interrupted perfection are now observable in you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Flawless Physiology:</b></i> The process of perfection eliminated all blemishes from your appearance, defined your musculature, and eradicated physiological weak points. Any curses, diseases, and similar afflictions currently affecting you immediately end. Furthermore, you gain immunity to the diseased condition.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i><b>Abrupt Optimization:</b></i> Your body has been permanently altered and optimized. From this moment onward, none of your Ability Scores can be lower than 10. If an effect would reduce one of your Ability Scores below 10, that Ability Score instead becomes 10 for the duration of the effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Blessing</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>
