<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<race>
	<name>Voidborn</name>
	<plural>Voidborn</plural>
	<description>Voidborn are tall and thin, with elongated limbs and large, expressive eyes that glow with an otherworldly light. Their skin is a pale, almost translucent blue-gray, and their hair is typically black or white.</description>
	<ability>
		<name>Teleportation</name>
		<description>As a bonus action, you can teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see.</description>
	</ability>
	<ability>
		<name>Psychic Resistance</name>
		<description>You have resistance to psychic damage.</description>
	</ability>
	<ability>
		<name>Otherworldly Resilience</name>
		<description>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed.</description>
	</ability>
	<background>
		<name>Interdimensional Travelers</name>
		<description>Voidborn were originally a race of interdimensional travelers, using their unique abilities to move through the void between worlds. However, something went wrong on one of their journeys, and they found themselves stranded in a strange, unfamiliar plane of existence. Over time, they adapted to their new environment, developing new physical traits and abilities that allowed them to survive and thrive in this new world.</description>
	</background>
	<culture>
		<name>Reclusive Society</name>
		<description>Voidborn are a reclusive race, preferring to keep to themselves and avoid contact with other races whenever possible. They have a deep reverence for the void, which they see as both a source of power and a dangerous force to be respected. Voidborn society is organized around small, tightly knit family groups, each with their own traditions and rituals.</description>
	</culture>
	<alignment>
		<name>Neutral</name>
		<description>Voidborn tend towards neutrality, seeing themselves as part of the larger cosmic balance. However, they are also fiercely protective of their own, and will go to great lengths to defend their families and their way of life.</description>
	</alignment>
</race>
