<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>revised feats</name>
    <description>Revised Feats from the HailJoe.</description>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.2">
      <file name="revised-feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-feats/revised-feats/revised-feats.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Great Weapon Master Revised" type="Feat" source="HailJoe Feats" id="ID_HAILJOE_FEAT_GREATWEAPONMASTER_REVISED">
    <description>
      <p>You’ve learned to put the weight of a weapon to your advantage, letting its momentum empower your strikes. You gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>On your turn, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make one melee weapon attack as a bonus action.</li>
        <li>Before you use your "Attack Action" to make a melee attack with a heavy weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to take a penalty equal to your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add double amount of your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.</li>
        <li>Note that this feat, does only works with action attacks. Bonus action attacks, reactions and other attacks that you're making not on your turn doesn't trigger the condition of this feat.</li>
        <li>On the other hand, some original attack patterns like "Flurry of Blows", even if they require a bonus action, will still be able to trigger this effect.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>On your turn, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make one melee weapon attack as a bonus action.
      Before you make a melee attack with a heavy weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to take a penalty equal to your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add double amount of your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Sharpshooter Revised" type="Feat" source="HailJoe Feats" id="ID_HAILJOE_FEAT_SHARPSHOOTER_REVISED">
    <description>
      <p>You have mastered ranged weapons and can make shots that others find impossible. You gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Attacking at long range doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.</li>
        <li>Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.</li>
        <li>Before you use your "Attack Action" to make an attack with a ranged weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to take a penalty equal to your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add the same amount of your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.</li>
        <li>Note that this feat only works with action attacks. Bonus action attacks, reactions, and other attacks that you make not on your turn do not trigger the condition of this feat.</li>
        <li>On the other hand, some original attack patterns like "Flurry of Blows", even if they require a bonus action, will still be able to trigger this effect.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Attacking at long range doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.
      Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.
      Before you make an attack with a ranged weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to take a penalty equal to your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add your proficiency bonus to the attack’s damage.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>
