<elements>
  <info>
    <name>weapons</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.16">
      <file name="weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/weapons/weapons.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Fang of the Dhampir" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FANG_OF_THE_DHAMPIR">
    <description>
      <p>This item appears to be a simple wooden stake with a carved silver tip. Upon closer inspection, the silver tip is actually a sharp fang, which appears to have been taken from a vampire or dhampir. The wooden stake is infused with magical energy that allows it to draw strength from the blood of the user's enemies.</p>
      <p>Effect: When the Fang of the Dhampir is used as a melee weapon, it grants the following benefits to a monk:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The user gains temporary hit points equal to their Wisdom modifier whenever they score a critical hit against a creature with blood flowing through their veins (excluding constructs and undead).</li>
        <li>The user can spend 1 ki point as a bonus action to gain advantage on their next attack roll with the Fang of the Dhampir against a creature with blood flowing through their veins (excluding constructs and undead).</li>
        <li>Once per day, the user can choose to infuse the Fang of the Dhampir with their own blood. Doing so grants the following additional benefits until the next dawn:</li>
        <ul>
          <li>The user gains resistance to necrotic damage.</li>
          <li>The user gains advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</li>
          <li>The user's unarmed strikes and attacks with the Fang of the Dhampir deal an additional 1d4 necrotic damage to creatures with blood flowing through their veins (excluding constructs and undead).</li>
        </ul>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
      <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Sanguinary Bloodreaper" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SANGUINARY_BLOODREAPER">
    <description>
      <p>The Bloodreaper is a longsword made of dark obsidian, almost vantablack in color. The blade is slightly curved and glimmers with a faint crimson sheen. The handle is wrapped in black leather, and the pommel is adorned with a red gemstone that seems to pulse with energy. The sword seems to sing a haunting melody when wielded in battle.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a hexblade warlock wields the Bloodreaper, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The sword is a +3 magic weapon made of obsidian.</li>
        <li>Whenever the user lands a successful hit with the sword, they regain 1d8 + Constitution modifier hit points.</li>
      </ul>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Blood Bond:</b></i> The sword has a special ability called Blood Bond. Whenever the user successfully hits a creature with the sword, they form a blood bond with that creature. While the bond is active, the user can use their bonus action to make a melee spell attack against the creature, dealing an additional 2d6 necrotic damage. The bond lasts for 24 hours or until the creature dies. If the user becomes unconscious, the bond vanishes immediately. This bonus action melee spell attack does not count as a "successful hit with the sword," so the user can't regain hit points by using the bonus attack.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Sanguine Strike:</b></i> The sword also has an ability called Sanguine Strike. Once per short or long rest, the user can teleport up to 15 feet forward and stab the sword into the ground. After the jump, all creatures within a 15-foot radius centered on the user are pushed 5 feet away from the center point, and all creatures in this area must make a Dexterity saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + the user's proficiency bonus + the user's Charisma modifier. On a failed saving throw, they take 6d6 necrotic damage, or half as much damage on a successful one. Creatures who succeed on the saving throw are not pushed away.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Bloodletting:</b></i> The sword has a passive ability called Bloodletting. Whenever the user is struck by a melee attack, they can use their reaction to make a melee attack against the attacker with the Bloodreaper. If the attack hits, the attacker takes an extra 1d6 necrotic damage, and the user regains hit points equal to the damage dealt. The user can only use this reaction when bonded with the "Blood Bond" ability; otherwise, the user can't use this reaction.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">3</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Soulrender (Dormant)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SOULRENDER_DORMANT">
    <description>
      <p>Soulrender is a mesmerizing weapon of shadow and steel. Its sleek black blade glimmers with an otherworldly sheen, adorned with meticulously etched engravings that dance with ethereal light. The hilt is wrapped in supple, obsidian-hued leather, and a single crimson gemstone, pulsating with arcane energy, rests in the pommel. As you grip the scythe, a whispered voice echoes in your mind, the sentience of the weapon stirring with curiosity and anticipation.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a hexblade warlock wields the Soulreaper (Dormant), they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>As a melee weapon, Soulrender functions as a +1 magic longsword/longbow. As a ranged weapon, it functions as a longbow with a range of 150/600 feet.</li>
        <li>Soulrender is a Sentient Weapon with an Intelligence score of 12, Wisdom score of 14, and Charisma score of 16. It can communicate telepathically with its wielder. It has hearing and darkvision to 120 ft.</li>
        <li>While attuned to Soulrender, hexblade warlocks and Oath of Vengeance paladins gain a +1 bonus to their spell attack rolls and saving throw DC for spells cast using their Pact Magic and Divine Magic features.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Soulrender (Awakened)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SOULRENDER_AWAKENED">
    <description>
      <p>Soulrender has undergone a profound metamorphosis, embodying both elegance and menace. The blade emanates an incandescent glow, a fusion of radiant and shadowy energies that intertwine with every stroke. The engravings upon its surface shimmer with arcane brilliance, evoking a sense of forbidden power. The hilt, now enveloped in a wispy, ethereal mist, grants an ethereal connection between wielder and weapon. The sentience within the scythe resonates with heightened awareness, a guide and companion in the arcane mysteries.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a hexblade warlock wields the Soulreaper (Awakened), they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>As a melee weapon, Soulrender functions as a +2 magic longsword/longbow. As a ranged weapon, it functions as a longbow with a range of 200/800 feet.</li>
        <li>Soulrender is a Sentient Weapon with an Intelligence score of 12, Wisdom score of 14, and Charisma score of 16. It can communicate telepathically with its wielder. It has hearing and darkvision to 120 ft.</li>
        <li>While attuned to Soulrender, hexblade warlocks and Oath of Vengeance paladins gain a +2 bonus to their spell attack rolls and saving throw DC for spells cast using their Pact Magic and Divine Magic features.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Additional Effects (in addition to the Dormant Version benefits):</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Awakening Resistance:</b></i> The user gains resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Heightened Curse:</b></i> When the user uses the "Hexblade's Curse" feature, the critical range extends to 18 rather than 19.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Divined Hex Strike:</b></i> Once per short rest, the wielder can use a bonus action to unleash a Divined Hex Strike. The next successful attack with Soulrender deals an additional 6d6 force or radiant damage.</p>    
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
    </rules> 
  </element>
  
  <element name="Soulrender (Exalted)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SOULRENDER_EXALTED">
    <description>
      <p>In its Exalted form, Soulrender stands as a pinnacle of divine craftsmanship and profane artistry. The blade is a tempest of intertwining shadows and radiant light, swirling in a mesmerizing dance that defies comprehension. Each etching upon the blade pulses with potent arcane energy, revealing the secrets of ancient magics. The hilt is now enshrouded in an ethereal mist, exuding an aura of raw power. As you grasp the scythe, the sentience within resonates with an amplified presence, an entity steeped in both wisdom and darkness, a willing partner in the pursuit of ascendance.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a hexblade warlock wields the Soulreaper (Exalted), they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>As a melee weapon, Soulrender functions as a +3 magic longsword/longbow. As a ranged weapon, it functions as a longbow with a range of 250/1000 feet.</li>
        <li>Soulrender is a Sentient Weapon with an Intelligence score of 12, Wisdom score of 14, and Charisma score of 16. It can communicate telepathically with its wielder. It has hearing and darkvision to 120 ft.</li>
        <li>While attuned to Soulrender, hexblade warlocks and Oath of Vengeance paladins gain a +3 bonus to their spell attack rolls and saving throw DC for spells cast using their Pact Magic and Divine Magic features.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>All Effects (in addition to the Dormant and Awakened Version benefits):</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Exalted Immunity:</b></i> The user gains immunity to necrotic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Heightened Curse:</b></i> When the user uses the "Hexblade's Curse" feature, the critical range extends to 18 rather than 19.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Divined Hex Strike:</b></i> Once per short rest, the wielder can use a bonus action to unleash a Divined Hex Strike. The next successful attack with Soulrender deals an additional 6d6 force or radiant damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Soul Devourer:</b></i> Once per long rest, the wielder can activate Soul Devourer. Upon hitting a target with Soulrender, they can choose to consume the target's soul, instantly killing them if they fail a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. If the target succeeds, they take an additional 10d6 necrotic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Shadow Blades of the Abundant Darkness:</b></i> The wielder gains the ability to summon Shadow Blades of the Abundant Darkness. Once per short rest, they can summon spectral blades that orbit around them, granting advantage on weapon attacks with Soulrender for 1 minute. There are 10 spectral blades that hover with Soulrender. The user can choose to use the blades for extra damage. Each blade deals an additional 1d6 necrotic damage and can travel with attacks. After a blade is used for an attack, the spectral blade vanishes immediately. The user can use more than one blade in a single turn.</p>    
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="enhancement">3</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_NECROTIC" />
    </rules> 
  </element>
  
  <element name="Infernal Baneblade" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_INFERNAL_BANEBLADE">
    <description>
      <p>The Infernal Baneblade is a finely crafted longsword forged from the darkest of metals and adorned with intricate, ominous engravings. Its hilt is wrapped in deep crimson leather, and a sinister ruby gemstone is embedded in the pommel. The blade itself seems to flicker with an internal flame, casting eerie shadows even in the brightest light.</p>
      <p>class="indent"><i><b>Effect:</b></i> When the user attunes to the Infernal Baneblade, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>As a melee weapon, Infernal Baneblade functions as a +2 magic longsword</li>
        <li>Infernal Baneblade is a Sentient Weapon with unknown stats. It can communicate telepathically with its wielder. It has hearing and Devil's Sight to 120 ft and he can see through the magical darkness.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>All Effects:</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Infernal Fury:</b></i> The sword deals an additional 2d6 fire damage on every successful hit, against fiends. This fire damage is considered magical and bypasses any fire resistance or immunity possessed by demons.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Demonbane Enchantment:</b></i> The Infernal Baneblade has been imbued with the essence of demonic creatures during its creation. As a result, it grants its wielder advantage on all attack rolls against demons.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Demonic Resonance:</b></i> When attuned to the Infernal Baneblade, the wielder gains resistance to fire damage, taking half damage from all fire-based attacks and effects.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Hellfire Strike:</b></i> Once per long rest, the wielder can channel the sword's demonic energy to deliver a devastating Hellfire Strike. This strike envelops the blade in raging flames and allows the wielder to make a single melee attack with advantage. If the attack hits, it deals an additional 4d6 fire damage, and the target must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or be set ablaze, taking an additional 2d6 fire damage at the start of each of its turns until it takes an action to extinguish the flames.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse of the Blood Hunger.</em></strong> This insidious curse, steeped in dark and ancient magic, ignites an unquenchable thirst within its unfortunate victim. From the moment it takes hold, an insatiable craving for the life essence of others consumes them. The cursed individual is driven to seek out fresh blood, be it from mortal veins or the pulsing hearts of creatures. As time goes on, the hunger grows more ravenous, slowly eroding their humanity and instilling a relentless predator's instinct. The curse distorts their thoughts, warping their once noble intentions into a primal obsession for sating their unending bloodlust. The cursed one is forever tormented by the dichotomy of their desires—a desperate longing for release from the curse's grip, while simultaneously reveling in the euphoria that accompanies the taste of warm, crimson life.</p>
      <p class="indent">When the Infernal Baneblade is equipped and attuned, with each kill that has taken by this swors wearer, "Infernal Baneblade" absorbs the blood. The user rolls for DC 16 Constitution saving throw. On failing save, causing the crystals to glow on the item, and increase the wearer's attack and damage bonus by +1 but reducing his max HP by -5, up to a 5 stacks, resetting each day. The user may willingly choose to fail this save.</p>
      <p class="indent">After a threshold of 5 is reached in one day, the sword would curse and bind itself to the wearer, making its effects permanent, but requiring a blood tax - either in the form of necrotic damage to the wearer, or forcing the character to kill a given number of creatures in required blood amount for every day. Each day, the wearer should kill at least 3 kills.</p>
      <p class="indent">For each day that user neglects the dark urge, the wearer has to make an DC 19 Constitution saving throw and take 2d6 necrotic damage or half as much in a success. Whether success or fails, the user also lose his/her max hit points equal amount to the damage recieves. The only way to gain lost hit points in this way, is feeding the relentless blood urge. The user has to feed the item with blood in sufficient amount which is 3 medium sized humanoid creatures blood. This sufficient amount stacks when the user doesn't feeds the item.</p>
      <p class="indent">If the item drains the wearers hit points to zero, it will consume their body and the sword becomes alive, a Chaotic Evil creature with equal amount the CR to the characters level or monster CR it just killed. It would echo the wearer's voice, but it would be a demonic entity that the ultimate demonic entities wishes. When the appeared demonic entity killed, the sword itself would return to being just as a sword, waiting to be used for its next victim.</p>
      <p class="indent">The person who died in this manner, can't return back from the death. Upon with his/her death, the users soul merges with the Evil creature, and when the user tried to turn back to life, Evil creature will return back instead of him/her. The users will and soul, shatters in the dark existance and will no longer be able to return...</p>
      <p class="indent">This item is impervious to magical effects and damage, even without the exception of a remove curse spell, which would normally detach the seal from its wearer and unattune from them automatically. But for this uncontrollable hunger, there is no solution except dying. Even after the dying, the users soul will be long gone. Only "Wish" spell could find a cure with an uncertain and unclear manner.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
    </rules> 
  </element>
  
  <element name="Rhapsody" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_RHAPSODY">
    <description>
      <p>This slender dagger, adorned with intricate ruBİES that shimmer like stardust, is a masterpiece crafted by an enigmatic artisan. The Rhapsody - Dagger possesses mystical properties that unfold in a majestic symphony of power and grace.</p>
      <p>All Effects:</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Scarlet Remittance:</b></i> Gain a +1 bonus to Attack Rolls, damage, and Spell Save DC for every foe you slay, up to a maximum of +3.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Sweet Bloodletting:</b></i> Possibly inflict Bleeding when hitting a creature with this weapon while Hiding or Invisible.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Bleeding Effect:</b></i> Takes 1d4 Slashing damage at the start of each turn and has Disadvantage on Constitution Saving Throws. At the end of the turn, creatures whose are bleeding, can roll Constitution Saving Throw equal to your spell save DC to end the bleeding effect. Can be removed by healing.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Sword of Answering (Replier)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SOA_REPLIER">
    <description>
      <p>In the world of Aiwelen, only nine of these blades are known to exist. Each is patterned after the legendary sword Fragarach, which is variously translated as "Final Word." Each of the nine swords has its own name and alignment, and each bears a different gem in its pommel.</p>
      <p>Replier is a True Neutral aligned sword, has a Peridot set in its pommel.</p>
      <p>Replier does not desire for its users to become attuned to itself. However, in exchange, the sword can only be held by fighters who are True Neutral aligned.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Effects:</b></i> You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this sword. In addition, while you hold the sword, you can use your reaction to make one melee attack with it against any creature in your reach that deals damage to you. You have advantage on the attack roll, and any damage dealt with this special attack ignores any damage immunity or resistance the target has.</p>
      <table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Name</td><td>Alignment</td><td>Gem</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Answerer</td><td>Chaotic good</td><td>Emerald</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Back Talker</td><td>Chaotic evil</td><td>Jet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Concluder</td><td>Lawful neutral</td><td>Amethyst</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Last Quip</td><td>Chaotic neutral</td><td>Tourmaline</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Rebutter</td><td>Neutral good</td><td>Topaz</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Replier</td><td>Neutral</td><td>Peridot</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Retorter</td><td>Lawful good</td><td>Aquamarine</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Scather</td><td>Lawful evil</td><td>Garnet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Squelcher</td><td>Neutral evil</td><td>Spinel</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="enhancement">3</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Wormfang Dagger" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_WORMFANG_DAGGER">
    <description>
      <p>A Wormfang Dagger is a weapon whose blade was made from the tooth of a dead sandworm from the south deserts of Malevolent Expanse. Wormfang Daggers are a highly valued choice of weapons for renowned assassins but they are really hard to come by.</p>
      <p>It is a +1 dagger that deals an additional 1d6 poison damage to any creature hit by it. Once per day, the dagger’s sand tremors ability can be activated by using an action.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Sand Tremors:</b></i> You cause a tremor in the ground around you in a ten foot radius. Each creature other than you in that area must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone. If the ground in that area is sand, it becomes difficult terrain for 1 hour.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Wyrmshide Bow" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_WYRMSHIDE_BOW">
    <description>
      <p>This bow is crafted with delicate dragon scales and strung with a fiber from a dragon's heart. While holding the bow, you can use a bonus action to speak its command word and channel the energy of the dragon within for 1 minute. When you do, the bow forms a draconic cowl of elemental energy around you. For the duration of the cowl, you gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>You gain 25 temporary hit points.</li>
        <li>You have resistance to damage of the same type as the elemental energy of the cowl. The type of energy is determined by the kind of dragon that provided the bow's scales, as shown on the table below.</li>
	<li>On a hit, the bow deals an extra 1d8 damage of the same type as the cowl's energy. If the target is a dragon, this extra damage ignores any resistance or immunity it has against that damage type.</li>
      </ul>
      <table>
				<thead>
				<tr><td>Dragon</td><td>Resistance</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Black</td><td>Acid</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Blue</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Brass</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Bronze</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Copper</td><td>Acid</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Gold</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Green</td><td>Poison</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Red</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Silver</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
	       	 		<tr><td>White</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
    </table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">shortbow</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="shortbow">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="weapon">Shortbow</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Faux Lunaire (Scythe, Shortbow)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FAUX_LUNARIE">
    <description>
      <p>The Faux Lunaire is a weapon of mystery and celestial majesty, echoing the moon in its transformations. The creators of this weapon are the lunar wardens, who have to fight creatures that are far beyond mere beasts.</p>
      <p>When you attune to this weapon, you will learn light cantrip. If you cast the light cantrip targeting this weapon, the carved runes activate. For the duration of the spell, as long as you hold the weapon, your Wisdom score increases by 2, to a maximum of 20, and you can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 60 feet.</p>
      <div class="reference">
	<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
      </div>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Trick Weapon:</b></i> The Faux Lunaire is a wickedly curved scythe crafted from an arcane alloy and engraved with lunar imagery and celestial runes. With a swift, spinning motion, the limbs of the blade and shaft of the scythe fold in and rotate around the grip, locking into place to form an ornate shortbow. As a bonus action, you can switch between the transformed and untransformed states of this weapon. As part of the bonus action, you can also magically teleport up to 10 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. In its untransformed state, this weapon is a scythe. In its transformed state, it’s a shortbow.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Untransformed:</b></i> Once on each of your turns when you damage a creature with this weapon, you can force it to make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw, becoming affected by the faerie fire spell on a failure. You do not need to concentrate on this spell, but it ends early if you put another creature under the effect of the spell, or if you fall unconscious.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Transformed:</b></i> In its transformed state, the Faux Lunaire has 2 charges. When you attack a creature with this bow, you can expend 1 charge to cast one of the following spells (save DC 17) from it (no action required): moonbeam or darkness. The spell is centered on the creature’s space and lasts until the end of your next turn. You do not need to concentrate on it, and you can only have one of these spells active at a time. If your attack misses, you expend the charge but the effect fails. The Faux Lunaire regains 1 expended charge each time it is targeted by the light cantrip.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">scythe</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="scythe">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="weapon">Scythe</set>
    </setters> 
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
      <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
    </rules> 
  </element>

  <element name="Valkørr’s Oath" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_VALKORRS_OATH">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">This weapon bears the final echo of a tyrant’s restraint — wield it wisely, lest the land break under your hand.</p>
      <p>This massive hammer crackles with residual heat and pressure. Forged from obsidian and rune-bound steel, its head glows faintly with dormant volcanic rune sigils.</p>
      <p>When you attuned to this weapon, you considered as proficient on Mauls. Additionally your Strength score is 19 while you wear these gauntlets. They have no effect on you if your Strength is already 19 or higher without them.</p>
      <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. This bonus does not consist on magical attacks. Also you can use this weapon as an arcane focus.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Sigil Warrior:</b></i> Whenever you hit a creature with this weapon, you can choose to erupt a rune. This maul has 5 rune sigils. When you erupt a rune, choose a target. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or take an additional 1d6 fire damage and be pushed 5 feet away from you.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Valkørr’s Fury:</b></i> Once per long rest, as an action, you can slam the hammer into the ground, causing a volcanic tremor. All creatures within 40 ft long 20 ft wide line must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or take 3d6 fire and 3d6 bludgeoning damage.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">maul</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="scythe">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by by a Cleric, Warlock or Paladin">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="weapon">Maul</set>
    </setters> 
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MAUL" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
      <stat name="strength:score:set" value="19" bonus="base" />
    </rules> 
  </element>

  <element name="Enspelled Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ENSPELLED_WEAPON">
    <description>
      <p>Bound into this weapon is a spell whose level ranges from Cantrip to 8th level. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
      <table>
				<thead>
				<tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spell Attack Bonus</td><td>Spell Save DC</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Cantrip</td><td>+5</td><td>DC 13</td></tr>
				<tr><td>1st Level</td><td>+5</td><td>DC 13</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd Level</td><td>+5</td><td>DC 13</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd Level</td><td>+7</td><td>DC 15</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th Level</td><td>+7</td><td>DC 15</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th Level</td><td>+9</td><td>DC 17</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6th Level</td><td>+9</td><td>DC 17</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th Level</td><td>+10</td><td>DC 18</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8th Level</td><td>+10</td><td>DC 18</td></tr>
    </table>    
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">spell, magic</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
      <set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}}</set>
    </setters> 
    <rules>
      <select type="Spell" name="Spell, Enspelled Weapon" supports="Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation" />
    </rules> 
  </element>

  <element name="Spellrender" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SPELLRENDER">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">These forty dark siblings, known only by the cold moniker of Spellrender, are the grim testament to the White Citadel's ceaseless campaign against the arcane arts. Forged in bitter seclusion by the shackled artisans of Wano—each blow of the hammer a coerced prayer for freedom—the steel catches the light with an unnatural, bleached luminescence. It is a sword of dread uniformity, possessing a duality that speaks volumes of its purpose: one edge is truth, honed for the swift dispatch of the corporeal, while the opposing serration is a coil of subtle, magical malice. Upon striking with this wicked reverse, the blade does not seek mere flesh; it inflicts a wound that is intrinsically resonant with the Weave, compelling the rawest essence of any subsequent spell to violently recoil upon its caster. Thus, the Spellrender ensures that the very act of defiance, the casting of a forbidden word, becomes the engine of the arcanist's own undoing.</p>
      <p>This magic weapon has the finesse property. When you equipped this weapon, you considered as proficient on Longswords. Also when you hit a creature with this weapon, you can choose to hit it with the inverted, serrated side of the blade: the damage from the attack is halved, and the target suffers a magical gash until the start of your next turn. The first time a creature begins to cast a spell while affected by the gash, the wound flares and deals 2d8 force damage to the target. Once you apply a gash, this property of the weapon can't be used again until the start of your next turn or until the target casts a spell.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="enhancement">0</set>
      <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters> 
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
    </rules> 
  </element>

  <element name="Whip of the Copper Eel" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_WHIP_OF_THE_COPPER_EEL">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">It is said that this whip was first forged in the heart of a sunken storm, where the breath of the sea met the crackle of the sky. The metal itself seems to weep with the memory of deep-water currents from the The Cobalt Abyss, always cool to the touch and unnervingly slick, yet possessing a startling kinetic grace. Tales speak of its first wielder, a Mage-Captain whose name is Royston the Parson, sought to make the very ocean his domain, and who could lash out with a coil of lightning that neither wave nor tide could smother. To hold it is to feel a restless, surging power, a silent promise that in the darkest depths, you shall still command the light.</p>
      <p>This magic whip hums with electricity. It has 4 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dawn. When you hit a creature with this whip, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to deal an extra 1d6 lightning damage to that creature for each charge you spend. You don't suffer the negative effects of underwater fighting when you make an attack with this weapon.</p>
	  <p>When you hit an underwater creature with this whip, it automatically takes an extra 1d6 lightning damage from the attack—as if you had expended a charge from it. When this happens, you can still spend charges from the whip to deal additional lightning damage to the creature. If you do, each other creature of your choice within 10 feet of the target must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or take lightning damage equal to half the amount dealt to the target.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">whip</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="enhancement">0</set>
      <set name="weapon">Whip</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Timepiercer" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_TIMEPIERCER">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">The origin of the Timepiercer is shrouded in the swirling dust storms of the Great Glass Waste, a place where the sun is said to shatter the hours into sand. It is rumored to be the final work of the reclusive chronomancers and dunamancers of the forgotten city of Aeterna, who sought not to conquer time, but to borrow brief, focused moments of it. The exquisite quartz hilt, forever holding its paradoxical hourglass, pulses with the faint echo of countless lost seconds. When its Command Word is uttered, the very essence of the dunes seems to answer, coalescing into a shimmering blade of perfectly arrested time. To wield it is to touch the hem of destiny, granting the holder the terrifying ability to either accelerate the world into a breathless blur or drag it into a grinding, heavy crawl—a power that must be treated with the solemn reverence reserved for the movements of the cosmos.</p>
      <p>This item appears to be a sword hilt that has a small hole on either end of it. The hilt is made of clear quartz and contains an hourglass with sand inside it. Despite the holes on the hilt, the sand never seems to flow out of the hourglass. You can speak the hilt's command word as a bonus action to cause it to form a thin blade made of sand at its end. The hourglass spills sand from the bottom of the hilt that circulates up and around to form the guard and blade of the rapier before it returns to the hourglass again through the hole at the top of the hilt. You can speak the hilt's command word again to cause all the sand to return to the hourglass. While the blade is formed, you gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
	  <p>While holding the hilt, you can use it to cast the haste or slow spell (save DC 16). You have advantage on Constitution saving throws you make in order to maintain concentration on a spell cast in this way. Once a spell has been cast using the hilt, it can't be used to cast that spell again until the following dawn. The sands in the hourglass move quickly while you concentrate on a haste spell cast in this way, or more slowly when you concentrate on a slow spell.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">rapier</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="weapon">Rapier</set>
    </setters>
	<rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" />
	  <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  
</elements>
