<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>wondrous</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.27">
      <file name="wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/wondrous/wondrous.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Kabuto's Helmet" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_KABUTOS_HELMET">
    <description>
      <p>This helmet appears to be a traditional samurai kabuto, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The helmet is adorned with intricate silver and gold filigree, and the visor is inlaid with a clear crystal that glimmers in the light. The wearer of this helmet feels a powerful surge of energy, as if the spirit of an ancient warrior has been awakened within them.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a fighter wearing the Kabuto's Helmet takes the Attack action and attacks with a melee weapon, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The user can add their Wisdom modifier to the damage roll of their attacks.</li>
        <li>If the user reduces an enemy to 0 hit points with a melee attack, they gain temporary hit points equal to their fighter level + their Wisdom modifier.</li>
        <li>The user is immune to the Frightened condition.</li>
        <li>The user gains resistance to psychic damage.</li>
        <li>Once per day, the user can invoke the power of the Kabuto's Helmet to enter a state of heightened awareness. While in this state, the user gains the following benefits for 1 minute:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>You have advantage on all Wisdom (Perception) checks and initiative rolls.</li>
          <li>Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
          <li>You can make an additional attack as part of your Attack action.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
      <rules>
              <stat name="melee:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="ability" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
      </rules>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">head, helmet</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="7">7 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_CHOTFB">
    <description>
      <p>This hammer appears to be a well-worn blacksmith's hammer, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The hammer's head is made of a gleaming silver metal, and the handle is carved from a rare wood that is said to have magical properties. The hammer seems to almost vibrate with power in the hands of a skilled blacksmith.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a blacksmith wielding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith creates a weapon or armor, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The time required to create the item is halved.</li>
        <li>The final product is of exceptional quality, granting a +1 bonus to its AC or attack and damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The final product is imbued with a minor magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Additionally, while holding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith, the user gains the following benefits:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>The user gains proficiency in the Smith's Tools if they do not already have it.</li>
          <li>The user can cast the <em>identify</em> spell once per day as a ritual, without expending a spell slot.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>This hammer has 1d4+1 charges. The user can invoke the power of the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith and uses 1 charge of the hammer to create an exceptional masterpiece. When doing so, the user must spend 12 hours crafting a single weapon or armor. The final product is of very rare quality, granting a +2 bonus to its AC or its attack and damage rolls, and is imbued with a powerful magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</p>
      <p>However, the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a malevolent curse that afflicts its user. Whenever the user creates an item with the hammer, there is a chance that the item will become corrupted and unstable. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item created is cursed and has a detrimental effect on its user or whoever wields it. The nature of the curse is up to the DM's discretion and can range from minor annoyances to major setbacks.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the user's own creations begin to turn against them. Any item created by the user using the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a chance to turn on its creator. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item becomes sentient and seeks to harm the user or whoever wields it.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">hammer</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="charges">5</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Lunar Predator's Claw Tattoo" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_LPCT">
    <description>
      <p>Produced by a special needle, this tattoo once was called as Eldritch Claw Tattoo. After a special regard becomes a demand for "Vague Trader" -a drow thy liveth in Saphentitte-, this magic tattoo transformed to depicts clawlike forms and to other jagged shapes.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the needle to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the needle there throughout the attunement process. When the attunement is complete, the needle turns into the ink that becomes the tattoo, which appears on the skin.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your attunement to the tattoo ends, the tattoo vanishes, and the needle reappears in your space.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Magical Strikes.</em></strong> While the tattoo is on your skin, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks, and you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with unarmed strikes.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Lunar Predator's Maul.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can empower the tattoo for 1 minute. For the duration, each of your melee attacks with a weapon or an unarmed strike can reach a target up to 15 feet away from you, as inky tendrils launch toward the target. In addition, on a hit, your melee attacks deal an extra force damage equal to your hemocraft die depending on your level. Once this feature is used, this bonus action can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Lycanthropic Empowerment.</em></strong> The tattoo resonates with the primal power of lycanthropy, enhancing your bestial abilities. While empowered by the Eldritch Claw Tattoo, the features of your Lycan transformation gain the following benefits:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Enhanced Claws.</em></strong> The damage of your Crimson Rite-infused claw attacks, starts to shreds the skin and sunder the veins and starts victim to bleed up until thy remains bone and dust. This bleed effect, inflicts an extra necrotic damage equal to your hemocraft die depending on your level to its victim at the start of the victims turn. At the end of the victims turn, the victim rolls a Constitution Saving Throw equal to your hemocraft DC to end its effect.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Bloodhunter's Vigor.</em></strong> As an action, you can expend hit points equal to two times of your Bloodhunter level to regain one use of your Lunar Predator's Maul feature. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Curse of Eternal Bond.</b></i> Once attuned to this tattoo, the user finds that attempts to remove it are futile. Any effort to erase, dispel, or magically remove the tattoo is met with resistance, causing intense pain and leaving the tattoo untouched. Additionally, the tattoo cannot be covered or concealed by any means; it always remains visible.</p>
      <p>All Effects of the Curse of the Eternal Bond:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Painful Removal.</em></strong> If the user attempts to magically remove or dispel the tattoo, they suffer excruciating pain, taking 12d6 psychic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Inescapable Mark.</em></strong> Any attempts to cover or conceal the tattoo magically are unsuccessful. It always remains visible, even through illusions.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Persistent Presence.</em></strong> Even if the user dies and is brought back to life, independently from body, the tattoo reappears on their new or old body.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tattoo, unarmed</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an Order of the Lycan Bloodhunter">true</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Coin of Malakhar" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_COIN_OF_MALAKHAR">
    <description>
      <p>This silver coin has the head of a raven on one side and a dagger on the other. On a roll you would normally use a d20, flip a coin instead. Heads is a critical success (natural 20), tails is a critical fail (natural 1). Once you use this coin instead of a normal roll, you can’t do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">coin</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Flask of Rivers" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FLASK_OF_RIVERS">
    <description>
      <p>This common looking metal flask is always cool when you touch it. When opened and poured, this flask produces up to 2 gallons of cold and clear water. Once emptied, the flask refills in 1 hour.</p>
      <p>Any water poured from this flask that isn’t consumed within 1 hour turns into sand.</p>	    
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">flask</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Tent of Traveler" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_TENT_OF_TRAVELER">
    <description>
      <p>The Tent of Traveler looks like a regular two-person tent. Setting up the tent takes ten minutes of effort. But the tent is bigger on the inside. Upon stepping through the entrance flap, you find yourself in a larger than expected space - containing 300 sq ft of floor room and a 15ft high ceiling, with a small kitchen, separated outhouse, and a central hearth and sitting area. There are enough beds and accommodations for 6 people to sleep comfortably, even if more may fit physically.</p>
      <p>Rain will not enter through the roof and the temperature inside the tent is always warm and comfortable, never too hot or too cold.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the tent has a number of furnishings and furniture which are bound to it; these will remain inside at all times, and cannot be removed. If destroyed, the furniture will reappear the next time the tent is set up. Any objects left inside will be dumped out after the tent is dismantled. The Tent of Traveler can be destroyed like a mundane ordinary tent.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tent</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (White)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_WHITE">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Yellow)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_YELLOW">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Blue)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_BLUE">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Black)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_BLACK">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
				<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Psychic Quiver" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_PSYCHIC_QUIVER">
    <description>
      <p>When you pull a nonmagical arrow from this quiver and immediately make an attack with it, the target takes an extra 1d6 psychic damage on a hit. If you roll a 6 on the die, you can choose to target that creature with the detect thoughts spell (no concentration required). When you do, you can choose to force the creature to make a DC 13 Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you probe deeper into its thoughts. Regardless, this effect lasts until the start of your next turn or until you force another creature to make the saving throw. Hit or miss the arrow becomes nonmagical again immediately after the attack.</p>
      <p>Other types of ammunition containers of this kind exist, such as a psychic bolt case meant for crossbow bolts, though quivers are most common.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">quiver</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with an Intelligence score of 13 or higher">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Sun Eater's Soul" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SUN_EATERS_SOUL">
    <description>
      <p>This black metal ring is unnervingly matte, reflecting nothing even in the brightest of light. While wearing this ring, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you is hit with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the damage that creature takes from the attack. The ring can be used to halve damage three times and regains all uses daily at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sun Eater's Grace.</em></strong>You choose a creature to create bond with the Sun Eater. When you restore hit points to a creature, you also restore that same number of hit points to a creature within 30 feet of you who is bonded to the Sun Eater. The ring can be used to restore hit points three times and regains all uses daily at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong>The ring resembles another ring as if not cursed, and cannot be detected as cursed item, other then Identify spell. At the end of every combat encounter, "for each reaction used" or "each time Sun Eater's Grace was activated", the wearer gains a random short-term madness from madness table. This Curse, cannot be undone by any regular spell, and spesifically needs to perform a ritual in one of the old sun temples. This ritual must be made in darkness spell for 24 hours, and a flesh sacrifice, must be served to Sun Eater. You need to sacrifice same level person or higher than you. You can also sacrifice an equivalent amount of CR or higher monster compare with your level. Sacrifice must be alive at the process. Completing this ritual, makes the Sun Eater stronger.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Removing the Ring.</em></strong>The wearer can remove the ring, but after the  removal, the wearer starts to lose 1d6 maximum hit points per day, which can only be stopped by casting Remove Curse or Greater Restoration. After the decaying is counter-measured, the lost hit points comes back at next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">ring</set>
      <set name="category">Rings</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Ring</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Curse of Moon-Blood (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_CURSE_OF_MOON_BLOOD_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p>During the early days of the scourge, not all the afflicted succumbed to beastly transformations. Many were driven mad, some were devoured by others, but the truly bloodthirsty—those who consumed the flesh of man and beast alike—became irreversibly twisted in both soul and body. These cannibals, driven by the need to survive, were cursed and became the first of the Crimson Beasts, also known as the Moon-Blooded. Their fate was sealed in monstrous deaths, each a grim reminder of their sins.</p>
      <p>One fateful day, all those who bore this curse were mysteriously slaughtered, their mangled remains half-buried in the ground. None knew the hand behind the massacre. In the aftermath, scholars of eldritch carvings discerned a pattern amidst the corpses, Martyr Tulio foremost among them.</p>
      <p>This eldritch rune, inscribed upon one’s flesh, grants control over the ancient curse. The bearer can shape their blood into deadly weapons and shields. However, spilling too much blood awakens the dormant curse, risking a transformation into the Crimson Beast of old.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>As a bonus action, you can unleash the power of the carving, transforming into a Crimson Beast. When you do, you take necrotic damage equal to one roll of your hit die, which cannot be reduced by any means. You suffer this damage again for every minute you remain transformed. This transformation ends early if you fall unconscious or use a bonus action to end it. While transformed, the blood you lose manifests in one of the following ways:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Barbed Tail.</em></strong>A barbed tail of blood erupts from your lower spine. As part of transforming and on subsequent turns as a bonus action, you can make a melee weapon attack with it. The tail is considered a simple melee weapon with which you are proficient. It has the finesse and reach properties, and it deals 1d8 magical piercing damage on a hit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Razor Claws.</em></strong>Your hands grow vicious claws. You gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, and your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 magical slashing damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>The power of the carving fortifies your body in dire moments. While attuned to this carving, your AC increases by 2 when your hit points are below half of your maximum.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Mephitic Seal (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MEPHITIC_SEAL_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p>This eldritch carving bears a single, rotting word of power. Legends say its utterance brings plagues and corruption, scarring the land and sickening all living beings. A rogue faction of manikins has unearthed the original carving and begun using its power to further their enigmatic agenda, much to the horror of mortal beings. Yet such power, if wielded wisely, could be turned against them—or doom all who try.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>You can use Miasma of Death feature.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Miasma of Death.</em></strong>As an action, you can summon a toxic miasma at a point you can see within 30 feet. The miasma forms a 15-foot-radius sphere that spreads around corners and lasts until the end of your next turn. Each creature fully within the miasma at the start of its turn must make a DC 18 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes poison damage equal to your proficiency bonus (in d6s) and is poisoned for the duration of the miasma. A poisoned creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. You can use this ability twice, regaining all expended uses after finishing a long rest. When you summon the miasma, you can choose one property from the following list to apply:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Obfuscation: The area becomes heavily obscured.</li>
        <li>Immunity: You are immune to the miasma's effects.</li>
        <li>Duration: The miasma lasts for 1 minute or until dispersed by moderate wind (10 mph or greater). As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the miasma 10 feet. If this carving is scarified, you can move it up to 30 feet instead.</li>
	<li>Radius: The radius of the miasma increases to 25 feet.</li>
        <li>Virulent: The damage dice become d12s instead of d6s.</li>
        <li>Lingering: On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and is not poisoned.</li>
      </ul>    
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>You can use the miasma a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses after finishing a long rest. Additionally, when summoning the miasma, you may apply two properties from now on. You do also gain new properties:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Corrosion: The miasma deals additional acid damage equal to your proficiency bonus (in d4s) on a failed save. Creatures that fail their save by 5 or more are blinded until the end of your next turn.</li>
        <li>Destruction: The miasma exudes a corrosive substance, destroying 1 inch of nonmagical wood, metal, or stone each round. While this property is active, the miasma ignores resistance and immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition. Constructs have disadvantage on their saving throw.</li>
      </ul> 
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Third Carving (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_THIRD_CARVING_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">War broke out in heaven. From the throne came flashes of lightning, and rumblings and peals of thunder, and before the throne were burning seven torches of radient fire. Mirabelle and her fellow angels fought against the corruption, and the fallen ones and their followers back. But she was not strong enough, and they lost their place in heaven. The forseken plunderer was hurled down—that ancient knife eared called the devil, who leads the whole world astray. He was hurled to the earth, and his lunatic fanatics with him. — Malleus Maleficarum</p>
      <p>The Third Carving is the embodiment of Mirabelle—the Left Hand of Kredite and the herald of punishment. It is said to bear the power of divine judgment, a shard of the conflict that once raged in heaven. Its power manifests as a fiery call to arms against those who defy the natural order, wielded only by those bold enough to endure its toll.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>When you roll initiative, you can choose to let the carving consume you for 1 minute (no action required). While consumed, you gain the following benefits. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Wings of Judgment.</em></strong>Fiery wings sprout from your back, granting you a flying speed of 30 feet. You can only use this speed to move toward a hostile creature you can see.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Seraphic Blade.</em></strong>A blade of eldritch—or perhaps divine—energy appears in your hand. This blade is a magic weapon with the finesse property. It deals 1d6 elemental and 1d6 psychic damage on a hit. Elemental damage could be; acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison and thunder, depending what would you pick amongst them.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>When you let the carving consume you, the benefits are enhanced:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Wings of Judgment Enhanced.</em></strong>Your flying speed increases to 60 feet, but you can still only use it to move toward a hostile creature you can see.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Righteous Punishment.</em></strong>When a creature damages you, you can use your reaction to release a psychic shockwave. The attacking creature must make an Intelligence saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, it takes psychic damage equal to your character level. On a success, it takes half as much damage. As part of the same reaction, you can stun the attacking creature until the end of your next turn. Once you stun a creature this way, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Seraphic Blade Enhanced.</em></strong>Your blade improves as follows:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The blade has the finesse and thrown (range 60/120) properties.</li>
        <li>The damage increases to 1d8 for both elemental and psychic.</li>
        <li>When thrown, the blade returns to your hand after the attack.</li>
	<li>Alternatively, you can fuse the blade with a nonmagical weapon you are holding. While fused, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls, and deals an extra 1d6 elemental and 1d6 psychic damage on a hit.</li>
      </ul> 
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Second Carving (Scarified)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SECOND_CARVING_SCARIFIED">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Its powers have fueled hubris, suffering, and tyranny across history. Most infamous was its possession by the Godless King, a mortal who dared declare himself divine. He ruled a world turned to ashes, for in his mind, desolation was preferable if it meant ruling as a god over the remnants.</p>
      <p>The Second Carving, known as the Voice of Creation, channels the omnipotent words that shaped existence. It is whispered to come from the scriptures of an ancient, long-lost civilization. This carving embodies the terrifying potential of creation—an echo of what lies beyond mortal comprehension.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>You gain the ability to comprehend and speak Celestial and Deep Speech. The carving imbues you with divine authority, allowing you to cast powerful decrees. Constitution or Wisdom (whichever is higher) is your spellcasting modifier for these abilities. Each decree can be used once per long rest, and they require only a verbal component.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>King’s Decrees.</em></strong>Here's the list of decrees:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Decree of Obedience: Command the heretic to kneel and worship. You cast the command spell, but you can use only the "grovel" command.</li>
        <li>Decree of Power: Bless your allies with destructive might. You cast Bless Spell from 1st lvl. Creatures under its effect reroll any 1s rolled on the d4 and must use the new result. However, they take 1d4 necrotic damage (this damage cannot be reduced) at the start of each of their turns.</li>
        <li>Decree of Blood: Bolster your soldiers to endure. You cast healing word on a willing creature. Until the end of that creature’s next turn, it gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls, but each time it takes damage, it suffers an additional 1d4 damage of the same type.</li>
      </ul> 
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>You gain the ability to speak Celestial and Deep Speech fluently.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Aegis of the Almighty.</em></strong>You gain resistance to radiant damage. At dawn each day, you can choose one creature within sight. That creature gains resistance to radiant damage while it remains within 10 feet of you and you are conscious. You can now use each decree a number of times equal to your Constitution or Wisdom modifier (whichever is higher). You regain all expended uses after a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Scarified).</em></strong>You embody the full might of the carving:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Aegis of the Almighty Enhanced.</em></strong>You gain resistance to radiant damage. Friendly creatures of your choice within 15 feet of you also have resistance to radiant damage while you are conscious. Additionally, you can amplify your decrees by expending two uses instead of one. Amplified effects are as follows:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Decree of Obedience.</em></strong>You can target a number of creatures equal to your Constitution or Wisdom modifier (whichever is higher) when you cast command.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Decree of Power.</em></strong>Creatures under bless gain an additional action on each of their turns. This action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action. The damage taken at the start of their turn increases to 2d4.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Decree of Blood.</em></strong>When you cast healing word, it is cast as if you're casting this at 7th level. The target gains a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls until the end of its next turn. Each time it takes damage, it suffers an additional 2d4 damage of the same type.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
              <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
	      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
      </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Tempest's Gale Essence" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_TEMPESTS_GALE_ESSENCE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Bound by the fury of the storm and the whispers of the wind, this shard crackles with the echoes of a forgotten tempest—awaiting the one who will command the sky’s wrath once more.</p>
      <p>Forged in the heart of a raging tempest, Tempest's Gale Essence is a crystalline shard imbued with the raw, untamed fury of the storm. Its surface shimmers with an ever-shifting glow, flickering with arcs of lightning that dance across its edges like caged thunder. When held, a faint vibration hums beneath the fingertips, as if the winds themselves whisper secrets of an ancient squall.</p>
      <p>Legends speak of a forgotten warrior who once wielded this essence—one who walked with the storm and commanded the sky’s wrath. Who knows, maybe this power lies dormant, waiting for the touch of one who can rekindle its slumbering might.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tempest Strike.</em></strong>Once per turn, when making a weapon or spell attack, the wielder may channel the storm’s wrath, dealing an additional 1d6 Lightning Damage on a successful hit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Windswept Ascent.</em></strong>Once per day, as a bonus action, the wielder can gain a flying speed of 30 feet (hover) for 1 minute. During this time, the wielder can also double their movement speed for only one turn with no action required. When wielder uses this feature, arcs of lightning crackle around their form, and the air trembles with the whisper of a distant thunderstorm.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tempest, lightning, thunder</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Inevitable Force Necklace" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_INEVITABLE_FORCE_NECKLACE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Forged deep within the heart of the frozen North, the Inevitable Force Necklace was a labor of both devotion and necessity. Orv Bezmadan, master smith and cleric of the Forge, saw in the raw, bitter magic of the North a force that could be channeled, but not tamed. Alongside his unlikely apprentice, Neryssa Snow—a scion of ancient draconic blood—they crafted the necklace as a conduit to weave inner strength into the biting cold of magic. While Orv hammered the silvered threads under sacred flames, Neryssa infused them with whispers of her lineage, the ancient breath of frost dragons pulsing within the metal. The result was an artifact that merged heart and ice: a boon to those who embraced their strength, but a beacon for forces drawn to overwhelming power.</p>
      <p>This intricate necklace is fashioned from braided silver threads, with a centerpiece resembling a frozen, swirling vortex. Upon attunement, a faint chill clings to the wearer’s presence.</p>
      <p>While attuned to this necklace, when you cast a spell that deals cold damage, you add your Charisma modifier to the damage dealt by the spell.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Flaws:</em></strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tempest Strike.</em></strong>Once per turn, when making a weapon or spell attack, the wielder may channel the storm’s wrath, dealing an additional 1d6 Lightning Damage on a successful hit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Windswept Ascent.</em></strong>Once per day, as a bonus action, the wielder can gain a flying speed of 30 feet (hover) for 1 minute. During this time, the wielder can also double their movement speed for only one turn with no action required. When wielder uses this feature, arcs of lightning crackle around their form, and the air trembles with the whisper of a distant thunderstorm.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">elemental, necklace, cold</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Amberblood Heart" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_AMBERBLOOD_HEART">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">It endured. So, too, shall you.</p>
      <p>This stone sculpture of a heart flows with slow-moving liquid amber. At its center is a crystalline amber core. As part of attuning to the heart, you must hold it against your chest for the duration. Once you attune to it, it magically vanishes into your chest to reinforce your heart and body; faint amber cracks then line your skin.</p>
      <p>While attuned to this item, you'll have the following abilities:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>You have resistance to acid and poison damage.</li>
        <li>You can't become diseased, petrified, or poisoned</li>
	<li>For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</li>
        <li>Your weight doubles.</li>
      </ul> 
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Amberblood Surge:</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can activate the heart's latent energy to encase yourself in hardening amber for 1 minute. During this duration, when you take damage in this state, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by 2d4 (minimum 2). You can use this reaction only once per turn and only transformed in this state. Additionally, while in this duration, your movement leaves behind temporary amber footholds, allowing you to move across liquids and vertical surfaces as if they were solid ground. This feature can be used once per day.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">poison, acid, heart, fire</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Gauntlets of the Frosted Magma Chain" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_GOTFMC">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">The chains that once bound the wind now anchor your foes in burning defiance.</p>
      <p>Forged from the crushed obsidian plates of Koralith’s armor, these gauntlets are etched with chain motifs glowing faintly like cold embers.</p>
      <p>While you're in some sort of trance or form (like Rage, Innate Sorcery, Superior Defense etc.), you gain +1 bonus to AC.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Magmatic Oppertunist:</b></i> When you miss an attack towards one creature, you can use your reaction to strike again to same creature at the beginning of the creatures turn. You can use this feature once in Short Rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Momentum Breaker:</b></i> Once per long rest, when you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, you may immediately use your reaction to either take the Hide action or Instantly move up to half your movement and gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">gauntlet, trance</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Argentflame Diadem" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ARGENTFLAME_DIADEM">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Even in death, the titan’s core roars — a gift to those who bend flame and fury alike.</p>
      <p>This magestic crown, jagged crystal pulses with inner flame. It was carved from the smoldering core of Koralith’s fused elemental soul.</p>
      <p>While attuned, when you cast a spell that deals fire, cold, lightning, or thunder damage, you may deal additional 1d4 damage as per instance. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Spellcasting modifier, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Blinding Shockwave:</b></i> Once per long rest, as a reaction to being hit by a melee attack, you can release a shockwave of heat. The attacker takes 2d8 fire damage and must succeed against your Spell Save DC Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the start of their next turn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Ember Refutation:</b></i> When casting a spell that deals fire damage, you can choose to make that spell ignore resistance to fire damage once per short rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">crown, fire, cold, lightning, thunder, shockwave</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by a Sorcerer or Wizard">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Sundering Cinder Ring" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SUNDERING_CINDER_RING">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Those who wait to be freed do not deserve freedom.</p>
      <p>This dark metallic ring has small veins of lava pulsing in a broken rhythm, forged from the ancient echo of destruction that still beats within ancestors heart.</p>
      <p>While attuned to this item, you can use its Unbounded Flames feature once per long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Unbounded Flames:</b></i> When you activete this feature, the unbounded eternal core flames coming from the Hearth-Forge starts to cleanse you and envelops your whole body. For 1 minute, you cleansed from all negative effects that effects you and you become immune to all negative effects. This effects could includes; curses, diseases, corruptions, madness etc. Also in this state, you become immune to fire damage and gain +1 to all of you physical attacks, magical attacks and Save DC's.</p>
      <p>Your negative effects does not vanishes and after 1 minute, you turn back to your previous state.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">ring, cleanse, dispel, fire, immune</set>
      <set name="category">Rings</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Ring</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Mark of the Silent Rebirth (Drawn)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MARK_OF_THE_SILENT_REBIRTH_DRAWN">
    <description>
      <p>Legends whisper of the last High Priest of Vidar, whose flesh was carved in the shape of the god’s own True Name at the moment Vidar fell silent. The rite did not restore the god, but it anchored the priest’s soul in the twilight between life and death — neither wholly living, nor truly gone. To bear this carving is to let the final breath of Vidar bind your body, defy decay, and channel the black flame of unmaking.</p>
      <p>To wear the Mark is to hear the echo of a god’s last breath. Vidar’s silence lingers in the carving’s cold touch—a reminder that even deities may fade, but their will lingers like a knife between the ribs. The black flame it wields is not yours to command; you are merely the hand that holds it, the voice that whispers its name. And when the fire flickers, you’ll wonder: does it answer your prayers… or is it the other way around?</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>While attuned to this carving in any form, you gain advantage on death saving throws and also you gain advantage against undead creatures.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Mark of the Silent Rebirth (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MARK_OF_THE_SILENT_REBIRTH_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p>Legends whisper of the last High Priest of Vidar, whose flesh was carved in the shape of the god’s own True Name at the moment Vidar fell silent. The rite did not restore the god, but it anchored the priest’s soul in the twilight between life and death — neither wholly living, nor truly gone. To bear this carving is to let the final breath of Vidar bind your body, defy decay, and channel the black flame of unmaking.</p>
      <p>To wear the Mark is to hear the echo of a god’s last breath. Vidar’s silence lingers in the carving’s cold touch—a reminder that even deities may fade, but their will lingers like a knife between the ribs. The black flame it wields is not yours to command; you are merely the hand that holds it, the voice that whispers its name. And when the fire flickers, you’ll wonder: does it answer your prayers… or is it the other way around?</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>While attuned to this carving in any form, you gain advantage on death saving throws and also you gain advantage against undead creatures.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>Vidar’s sigil shields your form at the brink of death. While you are below half your hit point maximum, you gain resistance to necrotic damage and your weapon attacks deal an additional 1d6 radiant or necrotic damage (your choice each attack). Additionally, whenever you restore hit points to a creature that is at 0 HP, they also gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier + your Cleric level.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Mark of the Silent Rebirth (Scarified)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MARK_OF_THE_SILENT_REBIRTH_SCARIFIED">
    <description>
      <p>Legends whisper of the last High Priest of Vidar, whose flesh was carved in the shape of the god’s own True Name at the moment Vidar fell silent. The rite did not restore the god, but it anchored the priest’s soul in the twilight between life and death — neither wholly living, nor truly gone. To bear this carving is to let the final breath of Vidar bind your body, defy decay, and channel the black flame of unmaking.</p>
      <p>To wear the Mark is to hear the echo of a god’s last breath. Vidar’s silence lingers in the carving’s cold touch—a reminder that even deities may fade, but their will lingers like a knife between the ribs. The black flame it wields is not yours to command; you are merely the hand that holds it, the voice that whispers its name. And when the fire flickers, you’ll wonder: does it answer your prayers… or is it the other way around?</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>While attuned to this carving in any form, you gain advantage on death saving throws and also you gain advantage against undead creatures.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>Vidar’s sigil shields your form at the brink of death. While you are below half your hit point maximum, you gain resistance to necrotic damage and your weapon attacks deal an additional 1d6 radiant or necrotic damage (your choice each attack). Additionally, whenever you restore hit points to a creature that is at 0 HP, they also gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier + your Cleric level.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Scarified).</em></strong>When inscribed via the scarification ritual, the Mark of the Silent Rebirth awakens Vidar’s blessing and curse fully and enables you to use Death's Rebirth feature.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Death's Rebirth.</em></strong>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, the carving flares with black fire. You immediately regain hit points equal to half your maximum HP and gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom score. For 1 minute:</p>
		<ul>
            <li>You are under the effect of Death Ward spell.</li>
            <li>You gain resistance to all damage except force damage.</li>
            <li>Your melee weapon attacks deal an additional 2d6 necrotic or radiant damage (your choice when you activate this feature).</li>
            <li>When the minute ends, you drop to 0 hit points and start making death saving throws as normal with advantage. You cannot benefit from this feature again until you finish a long rest.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Spirit Board" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SPIRIT_BOARD">
    <description>
      <p>This ornate wooden board has the letters of the Common alphabet printed on one side, alongside the words "Yes" and "No" and symbols representing "Weal" and "Woe." The board comes with a heart-shaped, wooden planchette. This planchette must be resting on the lettered side of the board for the board's magic to function.</p>
      <p>This board has 3 charges and regains 1 expended charge daily at dawn. While touching the planchette, you can take 1 minute to cast one of the spells on the table below. The table indicates how many charges you must expend to cast the spell. As you cast the spell, you call on the spirits of the dead to help guide the planchette across the board's surface, answering your questions by pointing to the letters or words on the board.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">SPELL</td><td>CHARGE COST</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td class="left">Augury</td><td>1</td></tr>
					<tr><td class="left">Commune</td><td>3</td></tr>
				</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">Augury, Commune, Spirit</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Moonwick Candle" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MOONWICK_CANDLE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">In the secret, shadowed cloisters of Zahlera's Weavers, the subtle arts of creation are always laced with a touch of divine mischief. Though their allegiance lies with the radiant deity of arcana, it is whispered that these artisans, in a gesture of familial respect—or perhaps quiet jest—crafted the Moonwick Candles for the devotees of Alluna, the silent sister of the sky. The candle is not poured, but grown, the gritty, cool wax drawn from moon-dusted earth found only in the secluded, lightless valley of White Linn’s Basin. When the flame ignites, it is not fire that consumes the wick, but a sliver of borrowed starlight: a gentle, unsettlingly cool azure that seems to drink the shadows around it. For the faithful of Alluna, this light is a physical manifestation of her distant gaze, allowing them to see through the night as if it were a thin veil. It is the perfect, temporary gift from one divine house to another, a brief, bright truce in the everlasting cosmic theatre.</p>
      <p>This candle is made from a gritty wax that, when burnt, creates a cool blue flame. Its hollow silver base is shaped in a crescent with star-shaped holes punched in its sides. While the candle burns, the holes in its base softly glow, and small twinkles of starlight burst from the flickering flame.</p>
      <p>The candle's magic is activated when the candle is lit, which requires an action. While lit, the candle sheds dim light in a 15-foot radius. Each creature within the candle's light gains darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</p>
      <p>After burning for 1 hour, the candle is destroyed. You can snuff it out early for use at a later time. Deduct the time it burned in increments of 1 minute from the candle's total burn time.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">candle, nightvision</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
	  <set name="slot">onehand</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Second Fiddle" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SECOND_FIDDLE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Within the austere, ivory walls of the White Citadel, under the watchful, unblinking gaze of the Inquisition, stands the hallowed Lasolfa College—a place where music is less an art and more a sacred, disciplined weapon. The Second Fiddle is not merely an instrument; it is the physical manifestation of a tradition known across the continent as the Sonata of the Eight Voices. Once every solstice, eight students, the most promising aspirants of their class, meet in the College's sunken amphitheater to engage in a grueling, dawn-to-dusk duel of melody and rhetoric. The prize for this melodic trial, a testament to technical mastery and sheer will, is this humble, worn fiddle. Its wood is not exotic, but it hums with the layered echoes of generations of talent, each scratch a victory, each imperfection a forgotten performance. When the victor of this Sonata finally holds it, the instrument seems to sigh, ready to lend its accumulated magic—a quickened note, a sudden surge of perfect pitch—to bolster their allies, a solemn reminder that even the most gifted soloist often requires the perfect 'second' voice to achieve true glory.</p>
      <p>A hand-me-down fiddle that's been enchanted over time by the sheer number of bards to have played it. You have a +3 bonus to Charisma (Performance) checks made with this fiddle. In addition, if you're a bard and are holding the fiddle when a creature other than you who can see and hear you rolls a Bardic Inspiration die, you can use your reaction to play a magical note on the fiddle. When you do, the creature can roll the Bardic Inspiration die again and choose either result. You can use this reaction before or after the creature rolls the Bardic Inspiration die, but before the GM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">viol, violin, instrument</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Amulet of the Fungal Heartstone" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_AMULET_OF_THE_FUNGAL_HEARTSTONE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">When Mortarossa, the Flesh-Shed Queen, finally succumbed to the stillness of death, her final shedding was not one of renewal, but of collapse. As her grand, fungal-choked form dissolved into a miasma of weeping spores, this amulet remained amidst the discarded husks—a singular, calcified fragment of her eldritch heart. The jade gem at its center still shivers with a sickening, rhythmic heat, as if the Queen’s consciousness continues to writhe within the stone, forever seeking a new vessel to graft itself upon. To wear the Heartstone is to feel the phantom weight of her decaying majesty; your skin hardens like the chitin of the abyss, and your breath carries the faint, sickly-sweet scent of the Marrow-Rot Gardens. It is a heavy crown for any victor, for while it guards the body against the ravages of poison and decay, it whispers of a hunger that even the grave could not silence—a promise that from the ruins of the old flesh, something far more terrible shall always bloom.</p>
      <p>This amulet is carved from the solidified exoskeleton of an Eldritch entity, containing a pulsating, jade-green gem at its center. The gem subtly shifts, appearing damp and alive.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Resilience.</em></strong>You gain +1 to your AC and have advantage on saving throws against the Poisoned and Necrotic damage dealing spells and conditions.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spore Sight (3/Long Rest).</em></strong>You can hurl concentrated poisonous spores at a point you can see within 120 ft. A 20 ft. radius sphere of spores erupts at chosen point. Each creature in the area must make a DC 16 Dexterity Saving Throw. On a failed save, they take 3d8 Poison Damage + 3d8 Necrotic Damage and are Poisoned. On a successful save, they take half damage and are not Poisoned.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">amulet, fungal, fungi</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
	  <set name="slot">neck</set>
    </setters>
	<rules>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Shard of Shifting Chroma" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SHARD_OF_SHIFTING_CHROMA">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Long ago, during the Cataclysm of the Prismatic Veil, it was whispered that the sky itself cracked like a fallen mirror, spilling the raw, unrefined hues of the cosmos into the world below. While many such splinters vanished into the annals of myth, the Flesh-Shed Queen, Mortarossa, was the one who plucked this jagged fragment from the smoldering crater where it fell, dragging it into the suffocating gloom of her Marrow-Rot Gardens. For eons, she hoarded the Shard as her most prized arcane theft, attempting to stifle its celestial brilliance with her own creeping corruption. Yet, the stone remained a cold and hungry void that drinks the very light it inhabits. To gaze into its depths now is to witness a trapped, defiant tempest; a violent, swirling vortex where the sapphire thunder of the High Peaks and the sun-gold fires of Aeterna clash eternally against the emerald stains of the Queen’s touch. To grasp the Shard is to reclaim a fragment of a storm that forgot how to end—a stolen relic that vibrates with a frantic, chaotic rhythm, waiting to unleash its spectrum of destruction upon the world it was once forbidden to see.</p>
      <p>This jagged, multifaceted crystal shard is unnaturally cold to the touch and seems to absorb the surrounding light. Its interior is a swirling vortex of intense, flickering shades of yellow, blue, and green, and their myriad derivatives. The colors shift and blur rapidly, hinting at uncontrollable energies trapped within.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Arcane Resonance.</em></strong>You can use this shard as an arcane focus. While holding it, you gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls and to the saving throw DCs of your spells.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Chaotic Surge (1/Short Rest).</em></strong>When you successfully hit a creature with a spell attack, or when a creature fails a saving throw against one of your spells, you can use a bonus action to expend the shard's charge. When you expand a charge, you roll a d4 in order to determine certain damage type. You gain advantage on your next spell attack roll or impose disadvantage on the next saving throw against one of your spells, determined by a d4 roll:</p>
	    <ul>
          <li><b><i>Yellow (Radiant/Fire).</i></b>Advantage or Disadvantage applies to a spell that deals Radiant or Fire damage.</li>
		  <li><b><i>Blue (Cold/Lightning).</i></b>Advantage or Disadvantage applies to a spell that deals Cold or Lightning damage.</li>
          <li><b><i>Green (Poison/Necrotic).</i></b>Advantage or Disadvantage applies to a spell that deals Poison or Necrotic damage.</li>
          <li><b><i>White (Any Spell).</i></b>Advantage or Disadvantage applies to a spell that deals any type of damage.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">focus, color</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
	  <set name="slot">onehand</set>
    </setters>
	<rules>
      <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="2" />
	  <stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="2" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Myceliaweave Circlet" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MYCELIWEAVE_CIRCLET">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Woven from the fibrous, yearning nerves of the Marrow-Rot Gardens, the Myceliaweave Circlet is no mere prize of war, but the true, undying essence of the Flesh-Shed Queen herself, seeking not a master, but a new vessel to inhabit. It is a silent architect of rot that once claimed a nameless mortal and sculpted her, through centuries of agonizing molts and grotesque transformations, into the entity the world feared as Mortarossa. To place it upon one's brow is to invite the white, searching threads of the mycelium to bridge the gap between wood and bone, stitching their cold, thrumming consciousness into the wearer's very thoughts until the distinction between the self and the soil’s hunger begins to dissolve. In its presence, the deadly nectar of the abyss becomes a restorative wine, fortifying the blood with a vigor that defies mortal frailty, yet this vitality is but a hollow lure—a creeping corruption that slowly replaces the wearer’s humanity with the silent, vegetative chorus of the deep. With a mere command, the circlet calls forth the dormant spores within the fallen, weaving rot into a blooming sentinel of moss and vine that mirrors the wearer's own inevitable decay. This crown is a jealous god; it does not merely sit upon the head but consumes it, digging its roots into the spirit to ensure that the new vessel shall walk the same path of shedding and sorrow, until they too are nothing more than a hollowed, fungal throne for the Queen's eternal reign.</p>
      <p>This fungus-covered wooden circlet is riddled with a tangled web of mycelia. While wearing it, you are always under the effects of the <em>Speak With Plants</em> spell. This version of the spell only allows you to understand and speak to fungi, instead of all plants. In addition, your Constitution score increases by 2, to a maximum of 22, and you are both immune to poison damage and condition. Whenever you would take poison damage, you can instead spend one Hit Die to magically regain hit points (no action required). When you do, roll the Hit Die, add your Constitution modifier, and regain a number of hit points equal to the total.</p>
	  <p>The circlet can also be used to cause new fungal growth to spring forth under your command. While wearing it, you can cause a patch of mushrooms and other fungi to grow from a 5-foot square of soil that you touch over the course of 1 minute. Alternatively, you can use this property to grow this fungus on a Large or smaller corpse. When you do, you can choose to reanimate that creature. This creature uses the statistics for a shambling mound, regardless of its previous form or abilities, with the exception that it has immunity to poison damage and regains hit points when subjected to poison damage, instead of lightning damage. It remains for 8 hours or until it's reduced to 0 hit points, at which point it collapses and can't be used as a target for this property again.</p>
	  <p>The reanimated creature is considered a fungus for the purposes of being able to communicate with it and is friendly to you and your companions. It obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any commands to the creature, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions. In combat, it shares your initiative count, but takes its turn immediately after yours. Once the circlet has been used to reanimate a creature in this way, it can't do so again until the next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">crown, fungi, mycelid</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
	  <set name="slot">head</set>
    </setters>
	<rules>
      <stat name="constitution" value="2" />
	  <stat name="constitution:max" value="2" />
	  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Kitsune Mask of the Silver Ghost" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_KITSUNE_MASK_OF_THE_SILVER_GHOST">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Deep within the Forest of the Whispering Silk, where the boundary between Wano and the Spirit Realm thins to a translucent veil, the air carries the scent of chilled ozone and ancient cedar. It was here, during the Rite of the Pale Mist—a night when the restless shadows of the woods threatened to swallow the very stars—that the great Yokai Shirogane-no-Yurei saw the tremor in young Sayuri’s hands. He did not offer words of hollow comfort, for his voice was the rustle of winter wind, but instead, he reached into the swirling silver mists and wove the spirit-energy into form. As he placed the Mask of the Silver Guardian into her trembling palms, the oppressive silence of the forest broke; the porcelain was warm, thrumming with the heartbeat of a protector who had been both mother and father to a child of two worlds. 'Wear this when the dark grows teeth, little spark,' the Yokai’s presence seemed to hum against her mind. Now, whenever Sayuri dons the mask, the terrifying vastness of Wano shrinks, replaced by the phantom warmth of a silver-white tail wrapped around her shoulders, and her fear ignites into a defiant, spectral fire that burns brighter than any mortal flame.</p>
      <p>This porcelain mask, painted with silver tears, does not hide the wearer; it reveals the world as it truly is.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Comfort of the White Silver.</em></strong>While wearing this mask, you have advantage on saving throws against being Frightened.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Foxfire Whispers.</em></strong>You can cast the Dancing Lights cantrip at will. The lights appear as small, floating blue-silver foxes.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spirit-Veil Vision.</em></strong>While wearing the mask, your eyes perceive the "Breath of the Unseen." You can see invisible creatures and objects within 60 feet of you. To your eyes, they appear as flickering, translucent silver outlines. Furthermore, you can see the "Spirit Tether" of any creature—a faint glowing cord that reveals if a creature is possessed, charmed, or under effect in any type of an illusion.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spirit Caller’s Resonance.</em></strong>If you are using your Innate Sorcery feature while wearing this mask, your magic starts to ignite with the Shirogane Foxfire:</p>
	    <ul>
          <li><b><i>Foxfire Lash.</i></b>Once per turn, when you hit a creature with a spell attack or a creature fails a saving throw against one of your spells, you deal an extra 1d6 Fire damage. This spiritual flame ignores fire resistance.</li>
		  <li><b><i>Soothing Embers.</i></b>When you deal this extra fire damage by this manner, you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to the fire damage dealt with this feature. But unlike normal temporary hit points, these can be added together (stacking) and last until your Innate Sorcery feature ends.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">fox, foxfire, kitsune</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
	  <set name="slot">head</set>
    </setters>
	<rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="The Wrath God's Mark (Drawn)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_WRATH_GODS_MARK_DRAWN">
    <description>
	  <p class="flavor">This strip of branded flesh, the sole remnant of the first vessel of Wrath, still pulses with the embers of an unquenchable fire. Legend tells that this mark was born from the hollow grief of a father who watched his children trampled during an Eldritch Hunt. In that moment, when pure sorrow curdled into unrestrained hatred, the man was forged into an instrument of ruin, blessed—or quizás cursed—with the strength to lay the world to waste. To halt the fury that was devouring his mind, the Radiant Church World’s Temple flayed the skin from his living frame and entombed him within their deepest vaults. To bear this mark is to feel more than your own blood coursing through your veins; it is to feel the low, ancient growl of vengeance. With every heartbeat, the carving grows warmer, promising the power to shatter all before you—yet demanding that you fling wide the gates of your mind to an eternal storm. Is this rage but a tool, or a master that consumes you piece by piece? Once this mark is etched into your form, you no longer merely fight; you become the scream of a god’s unfinished retribution.</p>
      <p>This strip of flesh, carved with jagged, thorn-like patterns, is said to be the remains of the first bearer of the powers of Wrath. Even now, the faint warmth of rage lingers in his flesh, as if he still thirsts for blood.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong> When you roll Initiative, you can let the mark consume you for 1 minute (no action required). You gain the following benefits:</p>
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Hand of Destruction.</strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make an additional attack as part of the same action.</li>
          <li><strong>Wrathful Resistance.</strong> Choose one damage type from among Bludgeoning, Piercing, or Slashing. You gain Resistance to that damage type.</li>
        </ul>
      <p>After the duration, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness. Once you use this carving, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, wrath, destruction</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="The Wrath God's Mark (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_WRATH_GODS_MARK_TATTOOED">
    <description>
	  <p class="flavor">This strip of branded flesh, the sole remnant of the first vessel of Wrath, still pulses with the embers of an unquenchable fire. Legend tells that this mark was born from the hollow grief of a father who watched his children trampled during an Eldritch Hunt. In that moment, when pure sorrow curdled into unrestrained hatred, the man was forged into an instrument of ruin, blessed—or quizás cursed—with the strength to lay the world to waste. To halt the fury that was devouring his mind, the Radiant Church World’s Temple flayed the skin from his living frame and entombed him within their deepest vaults. To bear this mark is to feel more than your own blood coursing through your veins; it is to feel the low, ancient growl of vengeance. With every heartbeat, the carving grows warmer, promising the power to shatter all before you—yet demanding that you fling wide the gates of your mind to an eternal storm. Is this rage but a tool, or a master that consumes you piece by piece? Once this mark is etched into your form, you no longer merely fight; you become the scream of a god’s unfinished retribution.</p>
      <p>The mark is tattooed onto your form, its jagged lines pulsing with a dull red glow when your temper rises. It no longer just sits upon your skin; it begins to weave into your very spirit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong> When you let the mark consume you (no action required when rolling Initiative), you gain the following improved benefits for 1 minute:</p>
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Chosen Nemesis.</strong> At the start of your turn, choose a Hostile creature you can see within 120 feet of you to serve as your nemesis. You have Advantage on attack rolls made against the chosen creature and on all saving throws against spells and other magical effects from the chosen creature. Once you choose a creature in this way, you can't choose a new creature until the previously chosen one has either died or 24 hours have passed.</li>
          <li><strong>Hand of Destruction.</strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make an additional attack as part of the same action.</li>
          <li><strong>Wrathful Resistance.</strong> You have Resistance to all Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.</li>
        </ul>
      <p>After the duration, you must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness. Once you use this carving, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, wrath, tattoo</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="The Wrath God's Mark (Scarified)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_WRATH_GODS_MARK_SCARIFIED">
    <description>
	  <p class="flavor">This strip of branded flesh, the sole remnant of the first vessel of Wrath, still pulses with the embers of an unquenchable fire. Legend tells that this mark was born from the hollow grief of a father who watched his children trampled during an Eldritch Hunt. In that moment, when pure sorrow curdled into unrestrained hatred, the man was forged into an instrument of ruin, blessed—or quizás cursed—with the strength to lay the world to waste. To halt the fury that was devouring his mind, the Radiant Church World’s Temple flayed the skin from his living frame and entombed him within their deepest vaults. To bear this mark is to feel more than your own blood coursing through your veins; it is to feel the low, ancient growl of vengeance. With every heartbeat, the carving grows warmer, promising the power to shatter all before you—yet demanding that you fling wide the gates of your mind to an eternal storm. Is this rage but a tool, or a master that consumes you piece by piece? Once this mark is etched into your form, you no longer merely fight; you become the scream of a god’s unfinished retribution.</p>
      <p>The mark is permanently carved into your flesh through a ritual of pain, making you a true vessel of destruction. The rage is no longer a temporary state; it is who you are.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Scarified).</em></strong> The mark imbues you, permanently granting you the benefits of the tattooed carving. Additionally, you gain the following benefit:</p>
        <ul>
		  <li><strong>Chosen Nemesis.</strong> At the start of your turn, choose a Hostile creature you can see within 120 feet of you to serve as your nemesis. You have Advantage on attack rolls made against the chosen creature and on all saving throws against spells and other magical effects from the chosen creature. Once you choose a creature in this way, you can't choose a new creature until the previously chosen one has either died or 24 hours have passed.</li>
          <li><strong>Hand of Destruction.</strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make an additional attack as part of the same action.</li>
          <li><strong>Wrathful Resistance.</strong> You have Resistance to all Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.</li>
          <li><strong>Ultimate Nemesis.</strong> When you choose a nemesis with your Chosen Nemesis benefit, attack rolls against you by creatures other than the nemesis have Disadvantage.</li>
        </ul>
      <p>At dawn each day, you must succeed on a DC 20 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, wrath, scarified, legendary</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

	<element name="Singularity Anchor" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_SINGULARITY_ANCHOR">
  		<description>
    		<p class="flavor">Singularity Anchor does not carry any light nor flame, but a hunger. It is a tether to the Great Nothingness, a weight that pulls not just upon the body, but upon the very light of the world. To hold the chain is to feel the persistent, shivering dread of the abyss, as the tiny void within the lantern patiently waits to devour the reality that dares to surround it.</p>
      		<p>This pitch-black iron lantern hangs from a heavy, cold-to-the-touch chain. Instead of a flame, a tiny, swirling singularity—a miniature black hole—hovers within its glassless frame, distorting the very light around it.</p>
      		<p class="indent"><strong><em>Devour Light.</em></strong> The lantern does not shed light. Instead, it consumes it. While the lantern is held open, it creates an aura of Magical Darkness in a 10-foot radius. Non-magical light sources within this radius are instantly extinguished.</p>
      		<p class="indent"><strong><em>Gravitational Pull.</em></strong> As an action, you can point the lantern at a creature within 30 feet. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Strength Saving Throw or be pulled 15 feet toward the lantern and knocked Prone.</p>
      		<p class="indent"><strong><em>Void Consumption.</em></strong> You can touch the lantern to a non-magical object that isn't being worn or carried and is no larger than a 1-foot cube. The singularity consumes the object, erasing it from existence.</p>
    	</description>
    	<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lantern, void, darkness, gravity</set>
    		<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      		<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      		<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
      		<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
	  		<set name="slot">hand</set>
    	</setters>
  	</element>

	<element name="Abyssal Cipher Key" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_ABYSSAL_CIPHER_KEY">
  		<description>
    		<p class="flavor">This jagged fragment of the logic that governs the Outer Dark, where locks are but suggestions and distance is a lie. The runes upon its obsidian surface do not merely glow; they writhe with the secrets of the first architects of the Void. It is a tool for those who realize that every door—and every breath of air—is merely a thin veil waiting to be unzipped by the cold, silent truth of the deep.</p>
      		<p>An obsidian key that feels unnaturally light. Pulsing purple Abyssal runes crawl across its surface like living insects. When held near a lock, the runes glow brightly, whispering secrets of the Void.</p>
      		<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Unlocking Void.</em></strong> You can use an action to insert this key into any mechanical or magical gates and doors. You can even unlock the doors and gates even if they have not any lock nor seal. The key casts the Knock spell without making any sound. Once used this way, it cannot be used again until the next dusk.</p>
        	<p class="indent"><strong><em>Abyssal Translator.</em></strong> While holding the key, you can read and understand Abyssal.</p>
        	<p class="indent"><strong><em>Void Passage.</em></strong> Once per day, you can use the key to "unlock" the air itself. You cast Rope Trick, but the entrance leads to a small, silent pocket of the Void instead of an extradimensional space. The space is pitch black and freezing cold, but safe from outside detection.</p>
    	</description>
    	<setters>
    		<set name="keywords">key, knock, open, abyssal, void</set>
    		<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      		<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      		<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
      		<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
	  		<set name="slot">hand</set>
    	</setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ROPE_TRICK" />
        </rules>
    </element>

	<element name="Signet of the Amethyst Gale" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_SIGNET_OF_THE_AMETHYST_GALE">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The ring itself is a remnant of the Great Void-Tempest, a celestial upheaval that tore through the amethyst skies of a forgotten realm. This ring does not grant power so much as it allows the wearer to become a conduit for the gale’s restless energy, turning every strike into a crackling echo of the void and every moment of pain into a sudden, sparking leap through the fabric of space.</p>
            <p>A jagged ring carved from a single piece of "Void-Obsidian." Violent arcs of purple lightning dance across its surface, occasionally leaping to the wearer’s skin, leaving behind faint, painless scars that hum with power.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Storm-Born Resistance.</em></strong> You have resistance to Lightning and Necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Hollow Strike.</em></strong> Once per turn, when you hit with a melee or ranged weapon attack, you can deal an extra 1d8 Lightning damage or 1d8 Necrotic damage of your choice.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Amethyst Blink.</em></strong> When you take damage, you can use your reaction to dissolve into a burst of purple sparks. You teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Any creature within 5 feet of the space you left must make a DC 17 Dexterity Saving Throw, taking 3d10 Lightning or Necrotic damage of your choice on a failed save. You can use this feature once per short rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="keywords">thunder, lightning, necrotic, violet, void</set>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>

	<element name="Tempest's Gale Essence (Awakened)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_TEMPESTS_GALE_ESSENCE_AWAKENED">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">What was once a mere splinter of a forgotten storm has become a thrumming, violet heart, awakened by the bittersweet resonance of a parting gift. As Oris pressed the crystalline shard into Zephyr’s palm for the final time, the faint whispers of the wind surged into a triumphant, ancestral choir, finally hailing the Herald they had long awaited. The essence no longer merely crackles; it breathes with the rhythmic fury of a hurricane, its silver radiance a testament to a bond that transcends physical distance. To hold it is to feel the sky’s own blood coursing through one's veins—a promise that wherever the wind blows, the power of the Storm Vessel remains shared, turning every strike into a jagged lash of divine wrath and every ascent into a soaring defiance of the earth. It is more than a weapon; it is the lingering echo of a friend’s faith, transformed into a celestial gale that shall never fall silent.</p>
            <p>This awakened essence hangs from a silver chain, the central shard thrumming with the power of a contained storm.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tempest Wrath.</em></strong> Once per turn, when you hit with a weapon or spell attack, you deal an extra 2d8 Lightning damage. If the target is wearing metal armor or is made of water/metal, this damage increases to 3d8.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Aero Kinetic Ascent.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you gain a flying speed of 60 feet (hover) for 1 minute. While flying, you are immune to being knocked Prone by wind-based effects. Additionally, once during this duration, you can move like a lightning bolt, moving up to your full speed as a free action; any creature you pass through must make a DC 16 Dexterity Saving Throw or take 4d6 Lightning damage and half as much on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Storm Vessel Synergy.</em></strong> Once per long rest, you can use your action to unleash the energy stored within the shard to protect your allies. Choose up to 3 creatures within 30 feet. For 1 minute, their weapons deal an additional 1d6 Lightning damage, and they gain Resistance to Lightning damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="keywords">thunder, lightning, storm, fly, hover</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
            <set name="slot">neck</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

	<element name="Gofu Hat" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_GOFU_HAT">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">This has is crafter from an ink made with the blood of a Celestial. Paper from trees grown in hallowed ground. Precise calligraphy honed with extensive practice. It’s not easy to make a genuine paper charm, but it’s certainly worth the trouble. There’s a reason why superstitious folk continue to scrawl their own imitations, hoping to achieve just a fraction of their power.</p>
            <p>When first found or crafted, this hat has 1d4 + 2 paper charms hanging from it, which provide good fortune and ward off evil. It regains 2 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Protective Talismans.</em></strong> While wearing the hat, you can use a bonus action to detach a charm and stick it on a willing creature within 5 feet of you, upon which the ink on it begins to glow softly. The creature gains the effects of the <em>Bless</em> spell and gains 1d6 temporary hit points until the start of your next turn, at which point the charm disintegrates. New charms reappears at dawn on hat.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">hat, wondrous, charm, talisman, celestial, bless, fortune</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="slot">Head</set>
            <set name="charges">6</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

	<element name="The Wrath God’s Mark (Drawn)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_WRATH_GODS_MARK_DRAWN">
        <description>
            <div class="sidebar">
				<p class="flavor">This strip of flesh, carved with jagged, thorn-like patterns, is said to be the remains of the first bearer of the powers of Wrath. The mark was branded upon a grieving father who lost his two children to the hooves of a Scourge beast after they foolishly ventured into the streets during a Hunt. Overcome by grief and rage, the mark transformed him into a vessel of destruction, granting him the strength to tear apart anything that stood before him. Yet such power demanded a price. The mark fed endlessly upon his sorrow, hollowing his mind and twisting his purpose into blind annihilation. Before he could unleash his fury upon the world, agents of the Radiant Church subdued him and flayed the cursed flesh from his body. But rather than destroy the mark, the Church recognized its terrible potential. Within their deepest sanctums, they began studying the carving, discovering that its wrath resonated violently with the essence of the Scourge. Through forbidden rites and relentless experimentation, they shaped the mark into a weapon—a controlled conduit of fury meant to turn the Scourge’s own nature against it. Even now, the flesh radiates a faint, simmering heat. Those who bear it feel echoes of the original father’s grief and rage, a reminder that the power forged to fight monsters is never free from becoming one.</p>
				<p> —Archive Records of Murut Order</p>
			</div>
            <p><strong><em>Drawn Effect.</em></strong> When you roll Initiative, you can let the mark consume you for 1 minute (no action required). You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Hand of Destruction.</strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make an additional attack as part of the same action.</li>
                <li><strong>Wrathful Resistance.</strong> Choose one damage type from among Bludgeoning, Piercing, or Slashing. You gain Resistance to that damage type.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>After the duration, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness.</p>
            <p>Once you use this carving, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">eldritch, carving, tattoo</set>
            <set name="category">Eldritch Carvings</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="name-format">The Wrath God’s Mark</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Wrath God’s Mark (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_WRATH_GODS_MARK_TATTOOED">
        <description>
            <div class="sidebar">
				<p class="flavor">This strip of flesh, carved with jagged, thorn-like patterns, is said to be the remains of the first bearer of the powers of Wrath. The mark was branded upon a grieving father who lost his two children to the hooves of a Scourge beast after they foolishly ventured into the streets during a Hunt. Overcome by grief and rage, the mark transformed him into a vessel of destruction, granting him the strength to tear apart anything that stood before him. Yet such power demanded a price. The mark fed endlessly upon his sorrow, hollowing his mind and twisting his purpose into blind annihilation. Before he could unleash his fury upon the world, agents of the Radiant Church subdued him and flayed the cursed flesh from his body. But rather than destroy the mark, the Church recognized its terrible potential. Within their deepest sanctums, they began studying the carving, discovering that its wrath resonated violently with the essence of the Scourge. Through forbidden rites and relentless experimentation, they shaped the mark into a weapon—a controlled conduit of fury meant to turn the Scourge’s own nature against it. Even now, the flesh radiates a faint, simmering heat. Those who bear it feel echoes of the original father’s grief and rage, a reminder that the power forged to fight monsters is never free from becoming one.</p>
				<p> —Archive Records of Murut Order</p>
			</div>
            <p><strong><em>Tattooed Effect.</em></strong> When you let the mark consume you, you instead gain the following improved benefits for the duration (1 minute):</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Chosen Nemesis.</strong> At the start of your turn, choose a Hostile creature you can see within 120 feet of you to serve as your nemesis. You have Advantage on attack rolls made against the chosen creature and on all saving throws against spells and other magical effects from the chosen creature. Once you choose a creature in this way, you can't choose a new creature until the previously chosen one has either died or 24 hours have passed.</li>
                <li><strong>Hand of Destruction.</strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make two additional attacks as part of the same action.</li>
                <li><strong>Wrathful Resistance.</strong> You have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>After the duration, you must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness.</p>
            <p>Once you use this carving, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">eldritch, carving, tattoo</set>
            <set name="category">Eldritch Carvings</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="name-format">The Wrath God’s Mark</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Wrath God’s Mark (Scarified)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_WRATH_GODS_MARK_SCARIFIED">
        <description>
            <div class="sidebar">
				<p class="flavor">This strip of flesh, carved with jagged, thorn-like patterns, is said to be the remains of the first bearer of the powers of Wrath. The mark was branded upon a grieving father who lost his two children to the hooves of a Scourge beast after they foolishly ventured into the streets during a Hunt. Overcome by grief and rage, the mark transformed him into a vessel of destruction, granting him the strength to tear apart anything that stood before him. Yet such power demanded a price. The mark fed endlessly upon his sorrow, hollowing his mind and twisting his purpose into blind annihilation. Before he could unleash his fury upon the world, agents of the Radiant Church subdued him and flayed the cursed flesh from his body. But rather than destroy the mark, the Church recognized its terrible potential. Within their deepest sanctums, they began studying the carving, discovering that its wrath resonated violently with the essence of the Scourge. Through forbidden rites and relentless experimentation, they shaped the mark into a weapon—a controlled conduit of fury meant to turn the Scourge’s own nature against it. Even now, the flesh radiates a faint, simmering heat. Those who bear it feel echoes of the original father’s grief and rage, a reminder that the power forged to fight monsters is never free from becoming one.</p>
				<p> —Archive Records of Murut Order</p>
			</div>
            <p><strong><em>Scarified Effect.</em></strong> The mark imbues you, permanently granting you the benefits of the tattooed carving. Additionally, when you choose a nemesis with your Chosen Nemesis benefit, attack rolls against you by creatures other than the nemesis have Disadvantage.</p>
			<ul>
                <li><strong>Chosen Nemesis.</strong> At the start of your turn, choose a Hostile creature you can see within 120 feet of you to serve as your nemesis. You have Advantage on attack rolls made against the chosen creature and on all saving throws against spells and other magical effects from the chosen creature. Once you choose a creature in this way, you can't choose a new creature until the previously chosen one has either died or 24 hours have passed.</li>
                <li><strong>Hand of Destruction.</strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make two additional attacks as part of the same action.</li>
                <li><strong>Wrathful Resistance.</strong> You have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>At dawn each day, you must succeed on a DC 20 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">eldritch, carving, tattoo</set>
            <set name="category">Eldritch Carvings</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="name-format">The Wrath God’s Mark</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
        </rules>
    </element>

	<element name="Helm of the Fanatic Martyr" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ITEM_HELM_OF_THE_FANATIC_MARTYR">
        <description>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<p class="flavor">Before the searing corruption of the Scourge turned him into a wandering pyre of madness, Gideon Harrow was the 'Unblinking Sentinel'—the first and last line of defense for the Jaeger Corps. This helm was not merely forged for protection, but as a sensory crucible; its iron was tempered in the same righteous fires that Gideon used to cauterize the world’s hidden rot. The visor does not just filter light; it focuses the wearer’s soul into a singular, lethal point of tactical clarity, stripping away the illusions of the aberrant to reveal the festering truth beneath. Even after his death, the metal remains unnervingly warm, vibrating with the ghost-echoes of a zealot’s conviction. To don the Helm of the Fanatic Martyr is to see the world as the Jaeger did—not as a land of beauty, but as a dying patient in need of a final, fiery surgery. It grants the wearer the cold, mechanical precision of a master hunter and the iron-willed resolve to face the madness of the Eldritch Moon, demanding that one must first become a witness to the darkness before they can ever hope to burn it away.</p>
			</div>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Martyr’s Unblinking Gaze (2/Long Rest).</em></strong> As an action, you can force the helm’s visor to flare with a blinding, holy radiance. For 1 minute, you gain Truesight out to a range of 60 feet. As you can command followes, the flames emerges from the helm to shed Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. You can extinguish this light as a bonus action. You can use this feature twice per long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Jaeger’s Tactical Precision (Proficiency Bonus/Long Rest).</em></strong> The helm’s internal mechanisms analyze the movements of your prey with cold, mechanical efficiency. You gain a +2 bonus to initiative rolls. Additionally, as a bonus action, you can study a creature you can see within 60 feet of you. Make an Intelligence (Investigation) check with advantage to discern the target's vital weaknesses. If you already have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks from another source, you instead gain a +5 bonus to this check. The DC for this check is calculated as DC = 10 + the creature's Proficiency Bonus. If the creature’s nature or species is unknown to you, the DC increases by 5. On a successful check, you immediately learn if the creature has any damage vulnerabilities, resistances or immunities. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus per Long Rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Fanatic’s Resolve.</em></strong> While wearing this helm, you have Advantage on saving throws against being Frightened. Additionally, the iron will of the Jaegers remains etched into the metal, shielding your mind from the supernatural terror of the Hunt. You also have Advantage on saving throws against Madness saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">helm, head, jaeger, hunter, vision, madness</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      		<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="slot">Head</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">false</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="initiative" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
	
</elements>

