<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>wondrous</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.3">
      <file name="wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/wondrous/wondrous.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Kabuto's Helmet" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_KABUTOS_HELMET">
    <description>
      <p>This helmet appears to be a traditional samurai kabuto, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The helmet is adorned with intricate silver and gold filigree, and the visor is inlaid with a clear crystal that glimmers in the light. The wearer of this helmet feels a powerful surge of energy, as if the spirit of an ancient warrior has been awakened within them.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a fighter wearing the Kabuto's Helmet takes the Attack action and attacks with a melee weapon, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The user can add their Wisdom modifier to the damage roll of their attacks.</li>
        <li>If the user reduces an enemy to 0 hit points with a melee attack, they gain temporary hit points equal to their fighter level + their Wisdom modifier.</li>
        <li>The user is immune to the Frightened condition.</li>
        <li>The user gains resistance to psychic damage.</li>
        <li>Once per day, the user can invoke the power of the Kabuto's Helmet to enter a state of heightened awareness. While in this state, the user gains the following benefits for 1 minute:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>You have advantage on all Wisdom (Perception) checks and initiative rolls.</li>
          <li>Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
          <li>You can make an additional attack as part of your Attack action.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
      <rules>
              <stat name="melee:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="ability" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FRIGHTENED" />
      </rules>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">head, helmet</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="7">7 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_CHOTFB">
    <description>
      <p>This hammer appears to be a well-worn blacksmith's hammer, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The hammer's head is made of a gleaming silver metal, and the handle is carved from a rare wood that is said to have magical properties. The hammer seems to almost vibrate with power in the hands of a skilled blacksmith.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a blacksmith wielding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith creates a weapon or armor, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The time required to create the item is halved.</li>
        <li>The final product is of exceptional quality, granting a +1 bonus to its AC or attack and damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The final product is imbued with a minor magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Additionally, while holding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith, the user gains the following benefits:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>The user gains proficiency in the Smith's Tools if they do not already have it.</li>
          <li>The user can cast the <em>identify</em> spell once per day as a ritual, without expending a spell slot.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>This hammer has 1d4+1 charges. The user can invoke the power of the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith and uses 1 charge of the hammer to create an exceptional masterpiece. When doing so, the user must spend 12 hours crafting a single weapon or armor. The final product is of very rare quality, granting a +2 bonus to its AC or its attack and damage rolls, and is imbued with a powerful magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</p>
      <p>However, the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a malevolent curse that afflicts its user. Whenever the user creates an item with the hammer, there is a chance that the item will become corrupted and unstable. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item created is cursed and has a detrimental effect on its user or whoever wields it. The nature of the curse is up to the DM's discretion and can range from minor annoyances to major setbacks.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the user's own creations begin to turn against them. Any item created by the user using the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a chance to turn on its creator. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item becomes sentient and seeks to harm the user or whoever wields it.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">hammer</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="charges">5</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
</elements>
