<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>wondrous</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.13">
      <file name="wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/wondrous/wondrous.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Kabuto's Helmet" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_KABUTOS_HELMET">
    <description>
      <p>This helmet appears to be a traditional samurai kabuto, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The helmet is adorned with intricate silver and gold filigree, and the visor is inlaid with a clear crystal that glimmers in the light. The wearer of this helmet feels a powerful surge of energy, as if the spirit of an ancient warrior has been awakened within them.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a fighter wearing the Kabuto's Helmet takes the Attack action and attacks with a melee weapon, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The user can add their Wisdom modifier to the damage roll of their attacks.</li>
        <li>If the user reduces an enemy to 0 hit points with a melee attack, they gain temporary hit points equal to their fighter level + their Wisdom modifier.</li>
        <li>The user is immune to the Frightened condition.</li>
        <li>The user gains resistance to psychic damage.</li>
        <li>Once per day, the user can invoke the power of the Kabuto's Helmet to enter a state of heightened awareness. While in this state, the user gains the following benefits for 1 minute:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>You have advantage on all Wisdom (Perception) checks and initiative rolls.</li>
          <li>Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
          <li>You can make an additional attack as part of your Attack action.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
      <rules>
              <stat name="melee:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="ability" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
      </rules>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">head, helmet</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="7">7 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_CHOTFB">
    <description>
      <p>This hammer appears to be a well-worn blacksmith's hammer, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The hammer's head is made of a gleaming silver metal, and the handle is carved from a rare wood that is said to have magical properties. The hammer seems to almost vibrate with power in the hands of a skilled blacksmith.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a blacksmith wielding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith creates a weapon or armor, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The time required to create the item is halved.</li>
        <li>The final product is of exceptional quality, granting a +1 bonus to its AC or attack and damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The final product is imbued with a minor magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Additionally, while holding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith, the user gains the following benefits:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>The user gains proficiency in the Smith's Tools if they do not already have it.</li>
          <li>The user can cast the <em>identify</em> spell once per day as a ritual, without expending a spell slot.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>This hammer has 1d4+1 charges. The user can invoke the power of the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith and uses 1 charge of the hammer to create an exceptional masterpiece. When doing so, the user must spend 12 hours crafting a single weapon or armor. The final product is of very rare quality, granting a +2 bonus to its AC or its attack and damage rolls, and is imbued with a powerful magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</p>
      <p>However, the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a malevolent curse that afflicts its user. Whenever the user creates an item with the hammer, there is a chance that the item will become corrupted and unstable. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item created is cursed and has a detrimental effect on its user or whoever wields it. The nature of the curse is up to the DM's discretion and can range from minor annoyances to major setbacks.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the user's own creations begin to turn against them. Any item created by the user using the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a chance to turn on its creator. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item becomes sentient and seeks to harm the user or whoever wields it.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">hammer</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="charges">5</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Lunar Predator's Claw Tattoo" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_LPCT">
    <description>
      <p>Produced by a special needle, this tattoo once was called as Eldritch Claw Tattoo. After a special regard becomes a demand for "Vague Trader" -a drow thy liveth in Saphentitte-, this magic tattoo transformed to depicts clawlike forms and to other jagged shapes.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the needle to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the needle there throughout the attunement process. When the attunement is complete, the needle turns into the ink that becomes the tattoo, which appears on the skin.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your attunement to the tattoo ends, the tattoo vanishes, and the needle reappears in your space.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Magical Strikes.</em></strong> While the tattoo is on your skin, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks, and you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with unarmed strikes.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Lunar Predator's Maul.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can empower the tattoo for 1 minute. For the duration, each of your melee attacks with a weapon or an unarmed strike can reach a target up to 15 feet away from you, as inky tendrils launch toward the target. In addition, on a hit, your melee attacks deal an extra force damage equal to your hemocraft die depending on your level. Once this feature is used, this bonus action can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Lycanthropic Empowerment.</em></strong> The tattoo resonates with the primal power of lycanthropy, enhancing your bestial abilities. While empowered by the Eldritch Claw Tattoo, the features of your Lycan transformation gain the following benefits:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Enhanced Claws.</em></strong> The damage of your Crimson Rite-infused claw attacks, starts to shreds the skin and sunder the veins and starts victim to bleed up until thy remains bone and dust. This bleed effect, inflicts an extra necrotic damage equal to your hemocraft die depending on your level to its victim at the start of the victims turn. At the end of the victims turn, the victim rolls a Constitution Saving Throw equal to your hemocraft DC to end its effect.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Bloodhunter's Vigor.</em></strong> As an action, you can expend hit points equal to two times of your Bloodhunter level to regain one use of your Lunar Predator's Maul feature. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Curse of Eternal Bond.</b></i> Once attuned to this tattoo, the user finds that attempts to remove it are futile. Any effort to erase, dispel, or magically remove the tattoo is met with resistance, causing intense pain and leaving the tattoo untouched. Additionally, the tattoo cannot be covered or concealed by any means; it always remains visible.</p>
      <p>All Effects of the Curse of the Eternal Bond:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Painful Removal.</em></strong> If the user attempts to magically remove or dispel the tattoo, they suffer excruciating pain, taking 12d6 psychic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Inescapable Mark.</em></strong> Any attempts to cover or conceal the tattoo magically are unsuccessful. It always remains visible, even through illusions.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Persistent Presence.</em></strong> Even if the user dies and is brought back to life, independently from body, the tattoo reappears on their new or old body.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tattoo, unarmed</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an Order of the Lycan Bloodhunter">true</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Coin of Malakhar" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_COIN_OF_MALAKHAR">
    <description>
      <p>This silver coin has the head of a raven on one side and a dagger on the other. On a roll you would normally use a d20, flip a coin instead. Heads is a critical success (natural 20), tails is a critical fail (natural 1). Once you use this coin instead of a normal roll, you can’t do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">coin</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Flask of Rivers" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FLASK_OF_RIVERS">
    <description>
      <p>This common looking metal flask is always cool when you touch it. When opened and poured, this flask produces up to 2 gallons of cold and clear water. Once emptied, the flask refills in 1 hour.</p>
      <p>Any water poured from this flask that isn’t consumed within 1 hour turns into sand.</p>	    
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">flask</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Tent of Traveler" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_TENT_OF_TRAVELER">
    <description>
      <p>The Tent of Traveler looks like a regular two-person tent. Setting up the tent takes ten minutes of effort. But the tent is bigger on the inside. Upon stepping through the entrance flap, you find yourself in a larger than expected space - containing 300 sq ft of floor room and a 15ft high ceiling, with a small kitchen, separated outhouse, and a central hearth and sitting area. There are enough beds and accommodations for 6 people to sleep comfortably, even if more may fit physically.</p>
      <p>Rain will not enter through the roof and the temperature inside the tent is always warm and comfortable, never too hot or too cold.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the tent has a number of furnishings and furniture which are bound to it; these will remain inside at all times, and cannot be removed. If destroyed, the furniture will reappear the next time the tent is set up. Any objects left inside will be dumped out after the tent is dismantled. The Tent of Traveler can be destroyed like a mundane ordinary tent.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tent</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (White)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_WHITE">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Yellow)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_YELLOW">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Blue)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_BLUE">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Black)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_BLACK">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
				<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Psychic Quiver" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_PSYCHIC_QUIVER">
    <description>
      <p>When you pull a nonmagical arrow from this quiver and immediately make an attack with it, the target takes an extra 1d6 psychic damage on a hit. If you roll a 6 on the die, you can choose to target that creature with the detect thoughts spell (no concentration required). When you do, you can choose to force the creature to make a DC 13 Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you probe deeper into its thoughts. Regardless, this effect lasts until the start of your next turn or until you force another creature to make the saving throw. Hit or miss the arrow becomes nonmagical again immediately after the attack.</p>
      <p>Other types of ammunition containers of this kind exist, such as a psychic bolt case meant for crossbow bolts, though quivers are most common.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">quiver</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with an Intelligence score of 13 or higher">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Sun Eater's Soul" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SUN_EATERS_SOUL">
    <description>
      <p>This black metal ring is unnervingly matte, reflecting nothing even in the brightest of light. While wearing this ring, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you is hit with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the damage that creature takes from the attack. The ring can be used to halve damage three times and regains all uses daily at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sun Eater's Grace.</em></strong>You choose a creature to create bond with the Sun Eater. When you restore hit points to a creature, you also restore that same number of hit points to a creature within 30 feet of you who is bonded to the Sun Eater. The ring can be used to restore hit points three times and regains all uses daily at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong>The ring resembles another ring as if not cursed, and cannot be detected as cursed item, other then Identify spell. At the end of every combat encounter, "for each reaction used" or "each time Sun Eater's Grace was activated", the wearer gains a random short-term madness from madness table. This Curse, cannot be undone by any regular spell, and spesifically needs to perform a ritual in one of the old sun temples. This ritual must be made in darkness spell for 24 hours, and a flesh sacrifice, must be served to Sun Eater. You need to sacrifice same level person or higher than you. You can also sacrifice an equivalent amount of CR or higher monster compare with your level. Sacrifice must be alive at the process. Completing this ritual, makes the Sun Eater stronger.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Removing the Ring.</em></strong>The wearer can remove the ring, but after the  removal, the wearer starts to lose 1d6 maximum hit points per day, which can only be stopped by casting Remove Curse or Greater Restoration. After the decaying is counter-measured, the lost hit points comes back at next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">ring</set>
      <set name="category">Rings</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Ring</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Curse of Moon-Blood (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_CURSE_OF_MOON_BLOOD_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p>During the early days of the scourge, not all the afflicted succumbed to beastly transformations. Many were driven mad, some were devoured by others, but the truly bloodthirsty—those who consumed the flesh of man and beast alike—became irreversibly twisted in both soul and body. These cannibals, driven by the need to survive, were cursed and became the first of the Crimson Beasts, also known as the Moon-Blooded. Their fate was sealed in monstrous deaths, each a grim reminder of their sins.</p>
      <p>One fateful day, all those who bore this curse were mysteriously slaughtered, their mangled remains half-buried in the ground. None knew the hand behind the massacre. In the aftermath, scholars of eldritch carvings discerned a pattern amidst the corpses, Martyr Tulio foremost among them.</p>
      <p>This eldritch rune, inscribed upon one’s flesh, grants control over the ancient curse. The bearer can shape their blood into deadly weapons and shields. However, spilling too much blood awakens the dormant curse, risking a transformation into the Crimson Beast of old.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>As a bonus action, you can unleash the power of the carving, transforming into a Crimson Beast. When you do, you take necrotic damage equal to one roll of your hit die, which cannot be reduced by any means. You suffer this damage again for every minute you remain transformed. This transformation ends early if you fall unconscious or use a bonus action to end it. While transformed, the blood you lose manifests in one of the following ways:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Barbed Tail.</em></strong>A barbed tail of blood erupts from your lower spine. As part of transforming and on subsequent turns as a bonus action, you can make a melee weapon attack with it. The tail is considered a simple melee weapon with which you are proficient. It has the finesse and reach properties, and it deals 1d8 magical piercing damage on a hit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Razor Claws.</em></strong>Your hands grow vicious claws. You gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, and your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 magical slashing damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>The power of the carving fortifies your body in dire moments. While attuned to this carving, your AC increases by 2 when your hit points are below half of your maximum.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Mephitic Seal (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_MEPHITIC_SEAL_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p>This eldritch carving bears a single, rotting word of power. Legends say its utterance brings plagues and corruption, scarring the land and sickening all living beings. A rogue faction of manikins has unearthed the original carving and begun using its power to further their enigmatic agenda, much to the horror of mortal beings. Yet such power, if wielded wisely, could be turned against them—or doom all who try.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>You can use Miasma of Death feature.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Miasma of Death.</em></strong>As an action, you can summon a toxic miasma at a point you can see within 30 feet. The miasma forms a 15-foot-radius sphere that spreads around corners and lasts until the end of your next turn. Each creature fully within the miasma at the start of its turn must make a DC 18 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes poison damage equal to your proficiency bonus (in d6s) and is poisoned for the duration of the miasma. A poisoned creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. You can use this ability twice, regaining all expended uses after finishing a long rest. When you summon the miasma, you can choose one property from the following list to apply:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Obfuscation: The area becomes heavily obscured.</li>
        <li>Immunity: You are immune to the miasma's effects.</li>
        <li>Duration: The miasma lasts for 1 minute or until dispersed by moderate wind (10 mph or greater). As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the miasma 10 feet. If this carving is scarified, you can move it up to 30 feet instead.</li>
	<li>Radius: The radius of the miasma increases to 25 feet.</li>
        <li>Virulent: The damage dice become d12s instead of d6s.</li>
        <li>Lingering: On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and is not poisoned.</li>
      </ul>    
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>You can use the miasma a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses after finishing a long rest. Additionally, when summoning the miasma, you may apply two properties from now on. You do also gain new properties:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Corrosion: The miasma deals additional acid damage equal to your proficiency bonus (in d4s) on a failed save. Creatures that fail their save by 5 or more are blinded until the end of your next turn.</li>
        <li>Destruction: The miasma exudes a corrosive substance, destroying 1 inch of nonmagical wood, metal, or stone each round. While this property is active, the miasma ignores resistance and immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition. Constructs have disadvantage on their saving throw.</li>
      </ul> 
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Third Carving (Tattooed)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_THIRD_CARVING_TATTOOED">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">War broke out in heaven. From the throne came flashes of lightning, and rumblings and peals of thunder, and before the throne were burning seven torches of radient fire. Mirabelle and her fellow angels fought against the corruption, and the fallen ones and their followers back. But she was not strong enough, and they lost their place in heaven. The forseken plunderer was hurled down—that ancient knife eared called the devil, who leads the whole world astray. He was hurled to the earth, and his lunatic fanatics with him. — Malleus Maleficarum</p>
      <p>The Third Carving is the embodiment of Mirabelle—the Left Hand of Kredite and the herald of punishment. It is said to bear the power of divine judgment, a shard of the conflict that once raged in heaven. Its power manifests as a fiery call to arms against those who defy the natural order, wielded only by those bold enough to endure its toll.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>When you roll initiative, you can choose to let the carving consume you for 1 minute (no action required). While consumed, you gain the following benefits. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Wings of Judgment.</em></strong>Fiery wings sprout from your back, granting you a flying speed of 30 feet. You can only use this speed to move toward a hostile creature you can see.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Seraphic Blade.</em></strong>A blade of eldritch—or perhaps divine—energy appears in your hand. This blade is a magic weapon with the finesse property. It deals 1d6 elemental and 1d6 psychic damage on a hit. Elemental damage could be; acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison and thunder, depending what would you pick amongst them.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>When you let the carving consume you, the benefits are enhanced:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Wings of Judgment Enhanced.</em></strong>Your flying speed increases to 60 feet, but you can still only use it to move toward a hostile creature you can see.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Righteous Punishment.</em></strong>When a creature damages you, you can use your reaction to release a psychic shockwave. The attacking creature must make an Intelligence saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, it takes psychic damage equal to your character level. On a success, it takes half as much damage. As part of the same reaction, you can stun the attacking creature until the end of your next turn. Once you stun a creature this way, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Seraphic Blade Enhanced.</em></strong>Your blade improves as follows:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The blade has the finesse and thrown (range 60/120) properties.</li>
        <li>The damage increases to 1d8 for both elemental and psychic.</li>
        <li>When thrown, the blade returns to your hand after the attack.</li>
	<li>Alternatively, you can fuse the blade with a nonmagical weapon you are holding. While fused, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls, and deals an extra 1d6 elemental and 1d6 psychic damage on a hit.</li>
      </ul> 
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Second Carving (Scarified)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SECOND_CARVING_SCARIFIED">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Its powers have fueled hubris, suffering, and tyranny across history. Most infamous was its possession by the Godless King, a mortal who dared declare himself divine. He ruled a world turned to ashes, for in his mind, desolation was preferable if it meant ruling as a god over the remnants.</p>
      <p>The Second Carving, known as the Voice of Creation, channels the omnipotent words that shaped existence. It is whispered to come from the scriptures of an ancient, long-lost civilization. This carving embodies the terrifying potential of creation—an echo of what lies beyond mortal comprehension.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Drawn).</em></strong>You gain the ability to comprehend and speak Celestial and Deep Speech. The carving imbues you with divine authority, allowing you to cast powerful decrees. Constitution or Wisdom (whichever is higher) is your spellcasting modifier for these abilities. Each decree can be used once per long rest, and they require only a verbal component.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>King’s Decrees.</em></strong>Here's the list of decrees:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Decree of Obedience: Command the heretic to kneel and worship. You cast the command spell, but you can use only the "grovel" command.</li>
        <li>Decree of Power: Bless your allies with destructive might. You cast Bless Spell from 1st lvl. Creatures under its effect reroll any 1s rolled on the d4 and must use the new result. However, they take 1d4 necrotic damage (this damage cannot be reduced) at the start of each of their turns.</li>
        <li>Decree of Blood: Bolster your soldiers to endure. You cast healing word on a willing creature. Until the end of that creature’s next turn, it gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls, but each time it takes damage, it suffers an additional 1d4 damage of the same type.</li>
      </ul> 
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Tattooed).</em></strong>You gain the ability to speak Celestial and Deep Speech fluently.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Aegis of the Almighty.</em></strong>You gain resistance to radiant damage. At dawn each day, you can choose one creature within sight. That creature gains resistance to radiant damage while it remains within 10 feet of you and you are conscious. You can now use each decree a number of times equal to your Constitution or Wisdom modifier (whichever is higher). You regain all expended uses after a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Eldritch Carving Effects (Scarified).</em></strong>You embody the full might of the carving:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Aegis of the Almighty Enhanced.</em></strong>You gain resistance to radiant damage. Friendly creatures of your choice within 15 feet of you also have resistance to radiant damage while you are conscious. Additionally, you can amplify your decrees by expending two uses instead of one. Amplified effects are as follows:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Decree of Obedience.</em></strong>You can target a number of creatures equal to your Constitution or Wisdom modifier (whichever is higher) when you cast command.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Decree of Power.</em></strong>Creatures under bless gain an additional action on each of their turns. This action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action. The damage taken at the start of their turn increases to 2d4.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Decree of Blood.</em></strong>When you cast healing word, it is cast as if you're casting this at 7th level. The target gains a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls until the end of its next turn. Each time it takes damage, it suffers an additional 2d4 damage of the same type.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">carving, curse</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Carving</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
              <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
	      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
      </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Tempest's Gale Essence" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_TEMPESTS_GALE_ESSENCE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Bound by the fury of the storm and the whispers of the wind, this shard crackles with the echoes of a forgotten tempest—awaiting the one who will command the sky’s wrath once more.</p>
      <p>Forged in the heart of a raging tempest, Tempest's Gale Essence is a crystalline shard imbued with the raw, untamed fury of the storm. Its surface shimmers with an ever-shifting glow, flickering with arcs of lightning that dance across its edges like caged thunder. When held, a faint vibration hums beneath the fingertips, as if the winds themselves whisper secrets of an ancient squall.</p>
      <p>Legends speak of a forgotten warrior who once wielded this essence—one who walked with the storm and commanded the sky’s wrath. Who knows, maybe this power lies dormant, waiting for the touch of one who can rekindle its slumbering might.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tempest Strike.</em></strong>Once per turn, when making a weapon or spell attack, the wielder may channel the storm’s wrath, dealing an additional 1d6 Lightning Damage on a successful hit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Windswept Ascent.</em></strong>Once per day, as a bonus action, the wielder can gain a flying speed of 30 feet (hover) for 1 minute. During this time, the wielder can also double their movement speed for only one turn with no action required. When wielder uses this feature, arcs of lightning crackle around their form, and the air trembles with the whisper of a distant thunderstorm.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tempest, lightning, thunder</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Inevitable Force Necklace" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_INEVITABLE_FORCE_NECKLACE">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Forged deep within the heart of the frozen North, the Inevitable Force Necklace was a labor of both devotion and necessity. Orv Bezmadan, master smith and cleric of the Forge, saw in the raw, bitter magic of the North a force that could be channeled, but not tamed. Alongside his unlikely apprentice, Neryssa Snow—a scion of ancient draconic blood—they crafted the necklace as a conduit to weave inner strength into the biting cold of magic. While Orv hammered the silvered threads under sacred flames, Neryssa infused them with whispers of her lineage, the ancient breath of frost dragons pulsing within the metal. The result was an artifact that merged heart and ice: a boon to those who embraced their strength, but a beacon for forces drawn to overwhelming power.</p>
      <p>This intricate necklace is fashioned from braided silver threads, with a centerpiece resembling a frozen, swirling vortex. Upon attunement, a faint chill clings to the wearer’s presence.</p>
      <p>While attuned to this necklace, when you cast a spell that deals cold damage, you add your Charisma modifier to the damage dealt by the spell.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Flaws:</em></strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tempest Strike.</em></strong>Once per turn, when making a weapon or spell attack, the wielder may channel the storm’s wrath, dealing an additional 1d6 Lightning Damage on a successful hit.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Windswept Ascent.</em></strong>Once per day, as a bonus action, the wielder can gain a flying speed of 30 feet (hover) for 1 minute. During this time, the wielder can also double their movement speed for only one turn with no action required. When wielder uses this feature, arcs of lightning crackle around their form, and the air trembles with the whisper of a distant thunderstorm.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">elemental, necklace, cold</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Amberblood Heart" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_AMBERBLOOD_HEART">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">It endured. So, too, shall you.</p>
      <p>This stone sculpture of a heart flows with slow-moving liquid amber. At its center is a crystalline amber core. As part of attuning to the heart, you must hold it against your chest for the duration. Once you attune to it, it magically vanishes into your chest to reinforce your heart and body; faint amber cracks then line your skin.</p>
      <p>While attuned to this item, you'll have the following abilities:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>You have resistance to acid and poison damage.</li>
        <li>You can't become diseased, petrified, or poisoned</li>
	<li>For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</li>
        <li>Your weight doubles.</li>
      </ul> 
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Amberblood Surge:</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can activate the heart's latent energy to encase yourself in hardening amber for 1 minute. During this duration, when you take damage in this state, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by 2d4 (minimum 2). You can use this reaction only once per turn and only transformed in this state. Additionally, while in this duration, your movement leaves behind temporary amber footholds, allowing you to move across liquids and vertical surfaces as if they were solid ground. This feature can be used once per day.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">poison, acid, heart, fire</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Gauntlets of the Frosted Magma Chain" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_GOTFMC">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">The chains that once bound the wind now anchor your foes in burning defiance.</p>
      <p>Forged from the crushed obsidian plates of Koralith’s armor, these gauntlets are etched with chain motifs glowing faintly like cold embers.</p>
      <p>While you're in some sort of trance or form (like Rage, Innate Sorcery, Superior Defense etc.), you gain +1 bonus to AC.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Magmatic Oppertunist:</b></i> When you miss an attack towards one creature, you can use your reaction to strike again to same creature at the beginning of the creatures turn. You can use this feature once in Short Rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Momentum Breaker:</b></i> Once per long rest, when you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, you may immediately use your reaction to either take the Hide action or Instantly move up to half your movement and gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">gauntlet, trance</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Argentflame Diadem" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ARGENTFLAME_DIADEM">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Even in death, the titan’s core roars — a gift to those who bend flame and fury alike.</p>
      <p>This magestic crown, jagged crystal pulses with inner flame. It was carved from the smoldering core of Koralith’s fused elemental soul.</p>
      <p>While attuned, when you cast a spell that deals fire, cold, lightning, or thunder damage, you may deal additional 1d4 damage as per instance. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Spellcasting modifier, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Blinding Shockwave:</b></i> Once per long rest, as a reaction to being hit by a melee attack, you can release a shockwave of heat. The attacker takes 2d8 fire damage and must succeed against your Spell Save DC Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the start of their next turn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Ember Refutation:</b></i> When casting a spell that deals fire damage, you can choose to make that spell ignore resistance to fire damage once per short rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">crown, fire, cold, lightning, thunder, shockwave</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by by a Sorcerer or Wizard">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Sundering Cinder Ring" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SUNDERING_CINDER_RING">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">Those who wait to be freed do not deserve freedom.</p>
      <p>This dark metallic ring has small veins of lava pulsing in a broken rhythm, forged from the ancient echo of destruction that still beats within ancestors heart.</p>
      <p>While attuned to this item, you can use its Unbounded Flames feature once per long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Unbounded Flames:</b></i> When you activete this feature, the unbounded eternal core flames coming from the Hearth-Forge starts to cleanse you and envelops your whole body. For 1 minute, you cleansed from all negative effects that effects you and you become immune to all negative effects. This effects could includes; curses, diseases, corruptions, madness etc. Also in this state, you become immune to fire damage and gain +1 to all of you physical attacks, magical attacks and Save DC's.</p>
      <p>Your negative effects does not vanishes and after 1 minute, you turn back to your previous state.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">ring, cleanse, dispel, fire, immune</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
</elements>

