<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>wondrous</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.8">
      <file name="wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/wondrous/wondrous.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Kabuto's Helmet" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_KABUTOS_HELMET">
    <description>
      <p>This helmet appears to be a traditional samurai kabuto, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The helmet is adorned with intricate silver and gold filigree, and the visor is inlaid with a clear crystal that glimmers in the light. The wearer of this helmet feels a powerful surge of energy, as if the spirit of an ancient warrior has been awakened within them.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a fighter wearing the Kabuto's Helmet takes the Attack action and attacks with a melee weapon, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The user can add their Wisdom modifier to the damage roll of their attacks.</li>
        <li>If the user reduces an enemy to 0 hit points with a melee attack, they gain temporary hit points equal to their fighter level + their Wisdom modifier.</li>
        <li>The user is immune to the Frightened condition.</li>
        <li>The user gains resistance to psychic damage.</li>
        <li>Once per day, the user can invoke the power of the Kabuto's Helmet to enter a state of heightened awareness. While in this state, the user gains the following benefits for 1 minute:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>You have advantage on all Wisdom (Perception) checks and initiative rolls.</li>
          <li>Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
          <li>You can make an additional attack as part of your Attack action.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
      <rules>
              <stat name="melee:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="ability" />
              <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
      </rules>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">head, helmet</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="7">7 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_CHOTFB">
    <description>
      <p>This hammer appears to be a well-worn blacksmith's hammer, but upon closer inspection, its craftsmanship is far superior to any mortal creation. The hammer's head is made of a gleaming silver metal, and the handle is carved from a rare wood that is said to have magical properties. The hammer seems to almost vibrate with power in the hands of a skilled blacksmith.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a blacksmith wielding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith creates a weapon or armor, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The time required to create the item is halved.</li>
        <li>The final product is of exceptional quality, granting a +1 bonus to its AC or attack and damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The final product is imbued with a minor magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Additionally, while holding the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith, the user gains the following benefits:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
          <li>The user gains proficiency in the Smith's Tools if they do not already have it.</li>
          <li>The user can cast the <em>identify</em> spell once per day as a ritual, without expending a spell slot.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>This hammer has 1d4+1 charges. The user can invoke the power of the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith and uses 1 charge of the hammer to create an exceptional masterpiece. When doing so, the user must spend 12 hours crafting a single weapon or armor. The final product is of very rare quality, granting a +2 bonus to its AC or its attack and damage rolls, and is imbued with a powerful magical enchantment of the DM's choice, appropriate to the item being crafted.</p>
      <p>However, the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a malevolent curse that afflicts its user. Whenever the user creates an item with the hammer, there is a chance that the item will become corrupted and unstable. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item created is cursed and has a detrimental effect on its user or whoever wields it. The nature of the curse is up to the DM's discretion and can range from minor annoyances to major setbacks.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the user's own creations begin to turn against them. Any item created by the user using the Cursed Hammer of the Fallen Blacksmith has a chance to turn on its creator. Roll a d4. On a roll of 1-2, the item becomes sentient and seeks to harm the user or whoever wields it.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">hammer</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="charges">5</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Lunar Predator's Claw Tattoo" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_LPCT">
    <description>
      <p>Produced by a special needle, this tattoo once was called as Eldritch Claw Tattoo. After a special regard becomes a demand for "Vague Trader" -a drow thy liveth in Saphentitte-, this magic tattoo transformed to depicts clawlike forms and to other jagged shapes.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the needle to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the needle there throughout the attunement process. When the attunement is complete, the needle turns into the ink that becomes the tattoo, which appears on the skin.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your attunement to the tattoo ends, the tattoo vanishes, and the needle reappears in your space.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Magical Strikes.</em></strong> While the tattoo is on your skin, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks, and you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with unarmed strikes.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Lunar Predator's Maul.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can empower the tattoo for 1 minute. For the duration, each of your melee attacks with a weapon or an unarmed strike can reach a target up to 15 feet away from you, as inky tendrils launch toward the target. In addition, on a hit, your melee attacks deal an extra force damage equal to your hemocraft die depending on your level. Once this feature is used, this bonus action can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Lycanthropic Empowerment.</em></strong> The tattoo resonates with the primal power of lycanthropy, enhancing your bestial abilities. While empowered by the Eldritch Claw Tattoo, the features of your Lycan transformation gain the following benefits:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Enhanced Claws.</em></strong> The damage of your Crimson Rite-infused claw attacks, starts to shreds the skin and sunder the veins and starts victim to bleed up until thy remains bone and dust. This bleed effect, inflicts an extra necrotic damage equal to your hemocraft die depending on your level to its victim at the start of the victims turn. At the end of the victims turn, the victim rolls a Constitution Saving Throw equal to your hemocraft DC to end its effect.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Bloodhunter's Vigor.</em></strong> As an action, you can expend hit points equal to two times of your Bloodhunter level to regain one use of your Lunar Predator's Maul feature. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Curse of Eternal Bond.</b></i> Once attuned to this tattoo, the user finds that attempts to remove it are futile. Any effort to erase, dispel, or magically remove the tattoo is met with resistance, causing intense pain and leaving the tattoo untouched. Additionally, the tattoo cannot be covered or concealed by any means; it always remains visible.</p>
      <p>All Effects of the Curse of the Eternal Bond:</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Painful Removal.</em></strong> If the user attempts to magically remove or dispel the tattoo, they suffer excruciating pain, taking 12d6 psychic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Inescapable Mark.</em></strong> Any attempts to cover or conceal the tattoo magically are unsuccessful. It always remains visible, even through illusions.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Persistent Presence.</em></strong> Even if the user dies and is brought back to life, independently from body, the tattoo reappears on their new or old body.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tattoo, unarmed</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an Order of the Lycan Bloodhunter">true</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Coin of Malakhar" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_COIN_OF_MALAKHAR">
    <description>
      <p>This silver coin has the head of a raven on one side and a dagger on the other. On a roll you would normally use a d20, flip a coin instead. Heads is a critical success (natural 20), tails is a critical fail (natural 1). Once you use this coin instead of a normal roll, you can’t do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">coin</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters> 
  </element>

  <element name="Flask of Rivers" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FLASK_OF_RIVERS">
    <description>
      <p>This common looking metal flask is always cool when you touch it. When opened and poured, this flask produces up to 2 gallons of cold and clear water. Once emptied, the flask refills in 1 hour.</p>
      <p>Any water poured from this flask that isn’t consumed within 1 hour turns into sand.</p>	    
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">flask</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Tent of Traveler" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_TENT_OF_TRAVELER">
    <description>
      <p>The Tent of Traveler looks like a regular two-person tent. Setting up the tent takes ten minutes of effort. But the tent is bigger on the inside. Upon stepping through the entrance flap, you find yourself in a larger than expected space - containing 300 sq ft of floor room and a 15ft high ceiling, with a small kitchen, separated outhouse, and a central hearth and sitting area. There are enough beds and accommodations for 6 people to sleep comfortably, even if more may fit physically.</p>
      <p>Rain will not enter through the roof and the temperature inside the tent is always warm and comfortable, never too hot or too cold.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the tent has a number of furnishings and furniture which are bound to it; these will remain inside at all times, and cannot be removed. If destroyed, the furniture will reappear the next time the tent is set up. Any objects left inside will be dumped out after the tent is dismantled. The Tent of Traveler can be destroyed like a mundane ordinary tent.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">tent</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (White)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_WHITE">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Yellow)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_YELLOW">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Blue)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_BLUE">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fungic Tea (Black)" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FUNGIC_TEA_BLACK">
    <description>
      <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
      <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of the affected madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter.</p>
      <p>However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC listed in the table below. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
      <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
				<tr><td class="left">TEA TYPE</td><td>SAVING THROW DC</td><td>AFFECTED MADNESS</td><td>RARITY</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td class="left">White</td><td>12</td><td>One short-term</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Yellow</td><td>14</td><td>All short-term; one long-term</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Blue</td><td>16</td><td>All short-term and long-term</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
				<tr><td class="left">Black</td><td>18</td><td>All short-term and long-term; one indefinite</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords"></set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">false</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Psychic Quiver" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_PSYCHIC_QUIVER">
    <description>
      <p>When you pull a nonmagical arrow from this quiver and immediately make an attack with it, the target takes an extra 1d6 psychic damage on a hit. If you roll a 6 on the die, you can choose to target that creature with the detect thoughts spell (no concentration required). When you do, you can choose to force the creature to make a DC 13 Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you probe deeper into its thoughts. Regardless, this effect lasts until the start of your next turn or until you force another creature to make the saving throw. Hit or miss the arrow becomes nonmagical again immediately after the attack.</p>
      <p>Other types of ammunition containers of this kind exist, such as a psychic bolt case meant for crossbow bolts, though quivers are most common.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">quiver</set>
      <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with an Intelligence score of 13 or higher">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Sun Eater's Soul" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_SUN_EATERS_SOUL">
    <description>
      <p>This black metal ring is unnervingly matte, reflecting nothing even in the brightest of light. While wearing this ring, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you is hit with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the damage that creature takes from the attack. The ring can be used to halve damage three times and regains all uses daily at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sun Eater's Grace.</em></strong>You choose a creature to create bond with the Sun Eater. When you restore hit points to a creature, you also restore that same number of hit points to a creature within 30 feet of you who is bonded to the Sun Eater. The ring can be used to restore hit points three times and regains all uses daily at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong>The ring resembles another ring as if not cursed, and cannot be detected as cursed item, other then Identify spell. At the end of every combat encounter, "for each reaction used" or "each time Sun Eater's Grace was activated", the wearer gains a random short-term madness from madness table. This Curse, cannot be undone by any regular spell, and spesifically needs to perform a ritual in one of the old sun temples. This ritual must be made in darkness spell for 24 hours, and a flesh sacrifice, must be served to Sun Eater. You need to sacrifice same level person or higher than you. You can also sacrifice an equivalent amount of CR or higher monster compare with your level. Sacrifice must be alive at the process. Completing this ritual, makes the Sun Eater stronger.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong><em>Removing the Ring.</em></strong>The wearer can remove the ring, but after the  removal, the wearer starts to lose 1d6 maximum hit points per day, which can only be stopped by casting Remove Curse or Greater Restoration. After the decaying is counter-measured, the lost hit points comes back at next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">ring</set>
      <set name="category">Rings</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="type">Ring</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
</elements>
