<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>weapons</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.1">
      <file name="weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/weapons.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Fang of the Dhampir" type="Magic Item" id="ID_HAILJOE_FANG_OF_THE_DHAMPIR">
    <description>
      <p>This item appears to be a simple wooden stake with a carved silver tip. Upon closer inspection, the silver tip is actually a sharp fang, which appears to have been taken from a vampire or dhampir. The wooden stake is infused with magical energy that allows it to draw strength from the blood of the user's enemies.</p>
      <p>Effect: When the Fang of the Dhampir is used as a melee weapon, it grants the following benefits to a monk:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The user gains temporary hit points equal to their Wisdom modifier whenever they score a critical hit against a creature with blood flowing through their veins (excluding constructs and undead).</li>
        <li>The user can spend 1 ki point as a bonus action to gain advantage on their next attack roll with the Fang of the Dhampir against a creature with blood flowing through their veins (excluding constructs and undead).</li>
        <li>Once per day, the user can choose to infuse the Fang of the Dhampir with their own blood. Doing so grants the following additional benefits until the next dawn:</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The user gains resistance to necrotic damage.</li>
        <li>The user gains advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</li>
        <li>The user's unarmed strikes and attacks with the Fang of the Dhampir deal an additional 1d4 necrotic damage to creatures with blood flowing through their veins (excluding constructs and undead).</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
      <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
</elements>
