<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>armors</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://github.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD">HailJoe</author>
    <update version="0.0.8">
      <file name="armors.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Santazma/HailJoe-DnD/main/hailjoe-items/armors/armors.xml"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Fangweave Armor" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_FANGWEAVE_ARMOR">
    <description>
      <p>Fangweave is a studded leather armor made from the hides of various lycan predators, such as wolves, bears, and rats The armor is adorned with razor-sharp fangs and claws, which have been carefully sewn into the leather to create a menacing appearance. When worn, the armor seems to take on a life of its own, as if the spirits of the creatures from which it was made have been imbued into the armor. The armor is lightweight and flexible, allowing for maximum mobility in combat, and is designed specifically for Blood Hunters and members of the Order of the Lycan. The fangs and claws of the armor also grant the user additional protection against beasts magical pyhsical attacks, and provide the wearer with enhanced senses and tracking abilities. The Fangweave is a symbol of the wearer's mastery of the hunt, and a warning to any who would dare to cross their path.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a Blood Hunter / Order of the Lycan class member wears the Fangweave, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The armor is a +1 magic armor.</li>
        <li>The user gains a +2 bonus to their Survival and Perception skills.</li>
        <li>The user can cast the <em>pass without trace</em> spell once per day without expending a spell slot.</li>
      </ul>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>Beast Warding:</b></i> The user gains resistance to all magical bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage dealt by beasts. In addition, the user has advantage on saving throws against being charmed, frightened, or paralyzed by beasts.</p>
      <p class="indent"><i><b>The Grim Resolve:</b></i> Once per long rest, when the wearer would be reduced to 0 hit points, they can use their reaction to instead drop to 1 hit point and enter a state of deathly determination. While in this state, if the Crimson Rite actives, the wearer gains their melee attacks deal one additional Hemocraft Die damage equal to your active Rite's damage type (Hemocraft Die increases with the wearer's Blood Hunter Level), and gain temporary hit points equal to their Blood Hunter level + their Constitution modifier (minimum of 1). This state of deathly determination lasts for 1 minute or until the wearer is knocked unconscious or killed. After the state ends, the wearer suffers one level of exhaustion. The Grim Resolve ability reflects the Blood Hunter's unwavering determination and willingness to defy death itself in order to achieve their goals.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
			<set name="keywords">studded, leather</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
      			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Order of the Lycan">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="studded leather">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">Studded Leather</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
      <stat name="perception:misc" value="2" />
      <stat name="survival:misc" value="2" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Armor of Wilds" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_ARMOR_OF_WILDS">
    <description>
      <p>This finely crafted armor resonates with the essence of nature itself, designed specifically to empower those who are attuned to the wilds. It embodies the harmony between the natural world and the druid who wears it, granting protection without compromising the connection to the primal forces.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a druid class member wears the Fangweave, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>The armor is a +1 magic armor.</li>
        <li>The user gains a +1 bonus to their Survival and Nature skills.</li>
        <li>The user gains bonus +4 AC in Wild Shape form, regardless from the animal type.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
			<set name="keywords">hide</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
      			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Druid">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="hide">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">Studded Leather</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
      <stat name="nature:misc" value="1" />
      <stat name="survival:misc" value="1" />
    </rules>
  </element>
	
  <element name="Aegis of the Eldritch Guardian" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_AEGIS_OF_THE_ELDRITCH_GUARDIAN">
    <description>
      <p>The Aegis of the Eldritch Guardian is a shield that is forged from the ironwood of Escar Forest, imbued with the essence of ancient protective magic. The shield's surface is etched with eldritch runes that glow faintly, providing an aura of otherworldly protection.</p>
      <p>Effect: When a paladin dons this shield, they gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b><i>Armor Class (AC) Bonus. </i></b> +1 to AC while wielding this shield.</li>
        <li><b><i>Eldritch Protection. </i></b> As a reaction, when you are hit by an attack from an eldritch horror or any creature with the Aberration type, you can activate the shield's magic to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, potentially causing it to miss. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once) per long rest.</li>
        <li><b><i>Guardian's Resolve. </i></b> Once per long rest, as an action, you can call upon the shield's guardian spirit. For the next minute, you gain resistance to psychic damage, and any creature that hits you with a melee attack takes psychic damage equal to your Charisma modifier.</li>
	<li><b><i>Spell Effect. </i></b> You can cast the <i>shield of faith</i> spell once per day without using a spell slot. When cast this way, the spell has a duration of 1 hour instead of the usual 10 minutes.</li>
	<li><b><i>Light of Protection. </i></b> As a bonus action, you can cause the shield to emit bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. This light lasts for 1 hour or until you dismiss it as a bonus action. While the shield is emitting light, you and allies within the bright light have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Paladin">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
	    		<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" />
      <stat name="ac:shield" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Bardic Leathers" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_BARDIC_LEATHERS">
    <description>
      <p>This armor has strands of spun mithral strung between its various studs, adding extra protection and allowing you to play it like a worn instrument. Even if you're not attuned to the armor, you gain a +2 bonus to AC while wearing it, and if you're proficient with lutes or lyres, you add your proficiency bonus to ability checks that involve playing the bardic leathers as an instrument.</p>
      <p>If you're attuned to the armor and have a free hand, you can use your reaction when you're hit by an attack to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration, using your hand to pluck one of the armor's strings. When you do, you can roll the Bardic Inspiration die and add the result to your AC, potentially causing the triggering attack to miss.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
			<set name="keywords">studded, leather</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
      			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Bard">true</set>
			<set name="type" addition="studded leather">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">Studded Leather</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Protector's Ward" type="Magic Item" source="HailJoe Items" id="ID_HAILJOE_PROTECTORS_WARD">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">The Protector's Ward is more than steel and iron; it is the crystallized promise of the de Courtenay lineage — a lesser noble family under Elgatus Family's patronage —, forged not in a smithy, but in the crucible of countless generations of sacrifice. Its surface, bearing the mirrored crest of two knights, tells the silent history of a house whose duty has always been to stand between danger and the vulnerable. It was first raised against the devastating wrath of the Godswars, deflected the shadow-wrought blades during the chaos of the Second Extinguishing, stood fast in the brutal press of the Drow Tunnel Incursions, and shone as a beacon of resistance during the desperate charge of the Rainbow Rebellion. To inherit this shield is to inherit a binding oath. When the time for succession arrives, the eldest receives the Ward, not as a symbol of power, but as a commitment to be the unmoving anchor in the storm. In battle, when a loved one is threatened, the shield responds, not with a simple block, but with an instantaneous, desperate transposition—placing the wielder exactly where the blow will land, a tradition of instantaneous, absolute self-sacrifice that is the true, enduring magic of the de Courtenay name.</p>
      <p>This shield depicts a pair of knights reflected across its center. While holding this shield, you can use your reaction when a friendly creature that you can see within 15 feet of you is hit by an attack from a hostile creature. You then teleport to the friendly creature's space, pushing it 5 feet away from you to an unoccupied space of your choice when you do. You take the damage from the attack, even if the total of the attack roll doesn't meet or exceed your AC. Once this property of the shield has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">hand</set>
      		<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="armor">Shield</set>
			<set name="enhancement">0</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	
</elements>
